<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>com.matthiasn.lotti</id>
  <metadata_license>CC-BY-SA-4.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0-only</project_license>
  <name>Lotti</name>
  <summary>A smart journal and life management app</summary>
  <description>
    <p>
      Lotti is a comprehensive life management and journaling application that helps you track your goals, 
      habits, and daily activities while maintaining your privacy. It features:
    </p>
    <ul>
      <li>Smart journaling with text, audio, and image support</li>
      <li>Habit tracking and goal management</li>
      <li>Health data integration</li>
      <li>Privacy-first design with local data storage</li>
      <li>Cross-platform synchronization</li>
      <li>Customizable dashboards and analytics</li>
    </ul>
    <p>
      Coming in December 2025: A 10-part blog series with video walkthroughs exploring everything Lotti can do — from task management to AI-powered insights. Learn how to take control of your productivity while keeping your data private!
    </p>
  </description>
  <developer id="com.matthiasn">
    <name>Matthias Nehlsen</name>
  </developer>
  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/matthiasn/lotti</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/matthiasn/lotti/issues</url>
  <url type="help">https://github.com/matthiasn/lotti</url>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">com.matthiasn.lotti.desktop</launchable>
  <icon type="stock">com.matthiasn.lotti</icon>
  <releases>
    <release version="0.9.757" date="2025-12-16">
      <description>
        <p>Nested AI Responses: Generated prompts from audio entries now display directly beneath them in an expandable section. Includes smooth collapse/expand animation and swipe-to-delete with confirmation.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.754" date="2025-12-15">
      <description>
        <p>Sync Backfill Improvements: EntryLink support ensures all sync message types are tracked and can be recovered. Ghost missing entry resolution handles cases where different message types share the same sequence counter.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.753" date="2025-12-14">
      <description>
        <p>Add prompt type for creating prompts, for example for feeding into Claude Code, Codex and
            similar tools, or ChatGPT, Gemini, Claude in research mode.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.752" date="2025-12-06">
      <description>
        <p>Sync Backfill: Request missing journal entries from connected devices during sync to ensure complete synchronization across all your devices.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.751" date="2025-12-05">
      <description>
        <p>Automatically create Gemini prompts.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.750" date="2025-12-05">
      <description>
        <p>Multiple improvements and simplifications in Sync code.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.747" date="2025-12-01">
      <description>
        <p>Automatic Image Analysis: Drop, paste, or import images to a task and they're analyzed automatically. Smart Task Summaries: Your first task summary is created immediately when you add meaningful content (image analysis, audio transcription, or text). No more manual checkbox clicks—just work naturally and let the AI keep up.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.746" date="2025-12-01">
      <description>
        <p>Checklist Correction Examples: The AI now learns from your manual corrections. When you fix a checklist item title (like "test flight" to "TestFlight"), Lotti remembers and uses these examples to improve future AI suggestions for both checklist updates and audio transcription.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.745" date="2025-11-30">
      <description>
        <p>Speech Dictionary per Category: Teach the AI your domain-specific terms. Add names, places, and technical words to a category's dictionary, and transcriptions automatically use the correct spellings. Select misrecognized text and add corrections via the editor context menu.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.744" date="2025-11-29">
      <description>
        <p>Smarter AI checklist updates: Say "I did the shopping" and the AI marks the right item complete. Mention "fix the typo in iPhone" and it corrects transcription errors. The AI now understands what you mean, not just what you type.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.743" date="2025-11-29">
      <description>
        <p>Improved task search field width and layout for better use of available space.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />
  <categories>
    <category>Office</category>
    <category>ProjectManagement</category>
    <category>Calendar</category>
  </categories>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>Lotti application interface</caption>
      <image type="source" width="536" height="999">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/matthiasn/lotti/8a5b9ef0f9d8e7132638f497107bc33215819c0d/flatpak/screenshot.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
</component>
