<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>com.matthiasn.lotti</id>
  <metadata_license>CC-BY-SA-4.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0-only</project_license>
  <name>Lotti</name>
  <summary>A smart journal and life management app</summary>
  <description>
    <p>
      Lotti is a comprehensive life management and journaling application that helps you track your goals, 
      habits, and daily activities while maintaining your privacy. It features:
    </p>
    <ul>
      <li>Smart journaling with text, audio, and image support</li>
      <li>Habit tracking and goal management</li>
      <li>Health data integration</li>
      <li>Privacy-first design with local data storage</li>
      <li>Cross-platform synchronization</li>
      <li>Customizable dashboards and analytics</li>
    </ul>
    <p>
      Coming in December 2025: A 10-part blog series with video walkthroughs exploring everything Lotti can do — from task management to AI-powered insights. Learn how to take control of your productivity while keeping your data private!
    </p>
  </description>
  <developer id="com.matthiasn">
    <name>Matthias Nehlsen</name>
  </developer>
  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/matthiasn/lotti</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/matthiasn/lotti/issues</url>
  <url type="help">https://github.com/matthiasn/lotti</url>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">com.matthiasn.lotti.desktop</launchable>
  <icon type="stock">com.matthiasn.lotti</icon>
  <releases>
    <release version="0.9.780" date="2025-12-29">
      <description>
        <p>Dashboard State Management Refactor: Migrated dashboard list state from Bloc to Riverpod for consistency with the codebase. Dashboard filtering and sorting now uses dedicated Riverpod providers, with improved case-insensitive sorting for better UX.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.779" date="2025-12-29">
      <description>
        <p>Labels for All Entry Types: Labels can now be assigned to any journal entry, not just tasks. Features include labels display on journal cards, edit capability in detail views, a new "Labels" action in the triple-dot menu, and a unified label selection modal with search and create functionality.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.778" date="2025-12-28">
      <description>
        <p>Twi Language Support: Added Twi (Akan) as a supported language for task summarization. Twi is spoken by approximately 9 million people in Ghana. Enables AI-generated task summaries in Twi with Ghana flag in the language selection UI.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.777" date="2025-12-28">
      <description>
        <p>Image Prompt Generation: New AI response type that transforms audio recordings and task context into detailed prompts for AI image generators like Midjourney, DALL-E 3, and Stable Diffusion. Features visual metaphor guidelines, multiple style options, and a convenient copy-to-clipboard button.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.776" date="2025-12-28">
      <description>
        <p>Task Summary Goal Section: AI task summaries now include a succinct Goal section after the TLDR. This 1-3 sentence description captures the desired outcome or essential purpose of the task, helping maintain focus on the "why" behind the work.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.775" date="2025-12-27">
      <description>
        <p>Single-User Multi-Device Sync: New room discovery feature allows Device B to find and join existing sync rooms without invitation. Includes confidence indicators, smart navigation, and bounded concurrency for faster discovery. Also fixes QR scanner restart after invite failures.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.774" date="2025-12-26">
      <description>
        <p>Calendar Privacy Filtering: Calendar view now respects category visibility settings from the Tasks page. Selected categories show colored boxes with text; unselected categories show colored boxes only (text hidden for privacy).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.773" date="2025-12-25">
      <description>
        <p>Checklist Correction UX: Corrections now use a delayed-save pattern with a cancel option. A 5-second countdown snackbar lets you discard accidental corrections before they're saved as AI learning examples.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.771" date="2025-12-23">
      <description>
        <p>Task Summary Link Extraction: AI summaries now include a Links section that automatically extracts and displays all URLs from task entries with succinct titles (e.g., "Linear: APP-123", "Lotti PR #456"). Links are deduplicated and formatted as clickable Markdown.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.770" date="2025-12-23">
      <description>
        <p>Upgraded to Flutter 3.38.5 with dependency updates. Sync refactoring: OutboxService.enqueueMessage() improved with Dart 3 pattern matching, extracted helper methods, and expanded test coverage (60 → 77 tests).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.768" date="2025-12-23">
      <description>
        <p>Gemini Thinking Support: All Gemini 2.5+ models (including Flash) now display AI reasoning in the Thoughts tab. Plus new usage statistics tracking shows token counts and processing duration for each AI response.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.765" date="2025-12-21">
      <description>
        <p>Sync: Live scans now process strictly after the last marker. The Matrix look-behind tail and its flag have been removed to eliminate redundant work.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.764" date="2025-12-21">
      <description>
        <p>Checklist Deletion Fix: Empty card containers no longer appear after deleting a checklist. The checklist ID is now properly removed from the parent task, and defensive UI filtering handles any existing stale references.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.762" date="2025-12-19">
      <description>
        <p>Sync Catch-Up Concurrency Fix: Prevents concurrent catch-up execution from multiple sources. External forceRescan calls now skip catch-up when an internal retry-driven catch-up is already in flight. Fixes timeout failures that occurred when connectivity triggers ran concurrently with scheduled catch-up retries.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.761" date="2025-12-18">
      <description>
        <p>Sync Catch-Up Fix: All catch-up paths now wait for the Matrix SDK to complete server sync before processing. Fixes issue where catch-up after extended offline periods would miss entries. Includes automatic follow-up for slow networks.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.758" date="2025-12-18">
      <description>
        <p>Sync Gap Detection Fix: Prevents false positive gap detection during reconnection. Covered vector clocks are now processed before gap detection, and live scan signals are deferred during catch-up to ensure in-order event processing.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.757" date="2025-12-16">
      <description>
        <p>Nested AI Responses: Generated prompts from audio entries now display directly beneath them in an expandable section. Includes smooth collapse/expand animation and swipe-to-delete with confirmation.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.754" date="2025-12-15">
      <description>
        <p>Sync Backfill Improvements: EntryLink support ensures all sync message types are tracked and can be recovered. Ghost missing entry resolution handles cases where different message types share the same sequence counter.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.753" date="2025-12-14">
      <description>
        <p>Add prompt type for creating prompts, for example for feeding into Claude Code, Codex and
            similar tools, or ChatGPT, Gemini, Claude in research mode.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.752" date="2025-12-06">
      <description>
        <p>Sync Backfill: Request missing journal entries from connected devices during sync to ensure complete synchronization across all your devices.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.751" date="2025-12-05">
      <description>
        <p>Automatically create Gemini prompts.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.750" date="2025-12-05">
      <description>
        <p>Multiple improvements and simplifications in Sync code.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.747" date="2025-12-01">
      <description>
        <p>Automatic Image Analysis: Drop, paste, or import images to a task and they're analyzed automatically. Smart Task Summaries: Your first task summary is created immediately when you add meaningful content (image analysis, audio transcription, or text). No more manual checkbox clicks—just work naturally and let the AI keep up.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.746" date="2025-12-01">
      <description>
        <p>Checklist Correction Examples: The AI now learns from your manual corrections. When you fix a checklist item title (like "test flight" to "TestFlight"), Lotti remembers and uses these examples to improve future AI suggestions for both checklist updates and audio transcription.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.745" date="2025-11-30">
      <description>
        <p>Speech Dictionary per Category: Teach the AI your domain-specific terms. Add names, places, and technical words to a category's dictionary, and transcriptions automatically use the correct spellings. Select misrecognized text and add corrections via the editor context menu.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.744" date="2025-11-29">
      <description>
        <p>Smarter AI checklist updates: Say "I did the shopping" and the AI marks the right item complete. Mention "fix the typo in iPhone" and it corrects transcription errors. The AI now understands what you mean, not just what you type.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.743" date="2025-11-29">
      <description>
        <p>Improved task search field width and layout for better use of available space.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />
  <categories>
    <category>Office</category>
    <category>ProjectManagement</category>
    <category>Calendar</category>
  </categories>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>Lotti application interface</caption>
      <image type="source" width="536" height="999">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/matthiasn/lotti/8a5b9ef0f9d8e7132638f497107bc33215819c0d/flatpak/screenshot.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
</component>
