<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>com.matthiasn.lotti</id>
  <metadata_license>CC-BY-SA-4.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0-only</project_license>
  <name>Lotti</name>
  <summary>A smart journal and life management app</summary>
  <description>
    <p>
      Lotti is a comprehensive life management and journaling application that helps you track your goals, 
      habits, and daily activities while maintaining your privacy. It features:
    </p>
    <ul>
      <li>Smart journaling with text, audio, and image support</li>
      <li>Habit tracking and goal management</li>
      <li>Health data integration</li>
      <li>Privacy-first design with local data storage</li>
      <li>Cross-platform synchronization</li>
      <li>Customizable dashboards and analytics</li>
    </ul>
    <p>
      Read the multi-part blog series with video walkthroughs exploring everything Lotti can do — from task management to AI-powered insights. Learn how to take control of your productivity while keeping your data private! See Substack link.
    </p>
  </description>
  <developer id="com.matthiasn">
    <name>Matthias Nehlsen</name>
  </developer>
  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/matthiasn/lotti</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/matthiasn/lotti/issues</url>
  <url type="help">https://matthiasnehlsen.substack.com/p/meet-lotti</url>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">com.matthiasn.lotti.desktop</launchable>
  <icon type="stock">com.matthiasn.lotti</icon>
  <releases>
    <release version="0.9.969" date="2026-04-21">
      <description>
          <p>Restores the task title edit affordance in the new DesktopTaskHeader. The read-only title now renders a trailing pencil icon next to the label, and empty titles display a localized "No title" placeholder in the same tappable slot so users have an obvious target to open the inline editor. Task list rows render the existing "(untitled)" label in the design-system error color and italic so missing titles stand out rather than silently collapsing the row.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.968" date="2026-04-20">
      <description>
          <p>Adds Phase 0 sync observability for the planned Inbound Event Queue redesign. MatrixStreamSignalBinder now records two additive probes on the sync room: a sync.limited log line with prevBatch, event count, and the time gap since the previous sync response whenever the Matrix server returns timeline.limited == true, and an onTimelineEvent.ordering summary every 100 events tracking strict reorderings and same-timestamp ties. Both route through the MATRIX_SYNC log domain into the dated sync log file. No behaviour change; data from ~48 hours of real use validates the two load-bearing SDK assumptions before the queue refactor starts.</p>
          <p>Fixes the desktop UI freezing during Matrix sync. The per-event apply loop in MatrixStreamProcessor used to hold the SQLite writer lock while awaiting attachment downloads, gzip decodes, and disk reads — on a 20-event catch-up slice this blocked user-driven journal saves for seconds at a time. SyncEventProcessor now splits into prepare (all I/O, no DB writes) and apply (pure DB writes); the pipeline runs prepare for a chunk in bounded-concurrency batches (4 at a time) outside the transaction, then opens a single transaction to apply the pre-resolved results. Outbox send-side gzip encode is also offloaded to a worker isolate for payloads above 2 KB. A regression test guards the invariant that every prepare completes before the writer transaction opens.</p>
          <p>Fixes live sync stalling until force-restart. The live-scan in-flight guard could stay set indefinitely if the apply pipeline hung on an unbounded Matrix attachment download — every subsequent timeline signal then coalesced silently and was dropped. All attachment downloads are now wrapped with a 45 s timeout that converts a hang into a retriable FileSystemException, and a stuck-scan watchdog releases the guard after 90 s so the pipeline recovers on its own rather than requiring a restart.</p>
          <p>Reduces sync log volume by roughly 40% at info level. The outbox send path used to emit about ten info lines per successful send across four subdomains; a single capture at the outbox processor now summarises the send with type, subject, retries, elapsed ms, and remaining pending queue depth. Per-event attachment.observe and attachmentIndex.record lines are gated behind a verboseLogging flag on AttachmentIngestor and AttachmentIndex; production wires this to false so steady-state and pagination-burst line counts drop, while tests keep the flag on to preserve existing per-event assertions. Failure, retry, and circuit-breaker diagnostics are unchanged.</p>
          <p>Sync signal sources consolidated. The live timeline only subscribes to append triggers (onNewEvent, onInsert); onChange, onRemove, and onUpdate had no legitimate driver in a single-user append-only sync model and are no longer wired. Their counters are dropped from the metrics snapshot and the liveScan.summary breakdown. The AppLifecycleRescanObserver widget was removed because the 30 s wake detector and connectivity-driven rescan already cover app resume; it was producing the forceRescan.skipped noise seen in recent logs.</p>
          <p>Adds a stateful inbound sync queue behind the USE_INBOUND_EVENT_QUEUE settings flag (default off). When the flag is on, live events, the limited=true bridge, and the new "Fetch all history" and "Catch up now" actions route through a Drift-backed queue with a single drain worker per room; per-room markers live in a new queue_markers table so commit and marker advance are atomic and monotonic. Encrypted events are held in a decryption pen until the Megolm session key arrives, so pre-decryption ciphertext never lands in the queue. The legacy live-scan pipeline is suppressed when the flag is on, keeping the two paths mutually exclusive. Sync Settings gains a flag-gated queue depth card plus Catch-up-now and Fetch-all-history actions. Pipeline-tagged log lines let the Phase-2 validation gate compare apply rates across the two paths.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.967" date="2026-04-20">
      <description>
          <p>Task detail header rebuilt against the desktop Figma:</p>
          <ul>
              <li>New DesktopTaskHeader replaces the pinned title sliver and legacy TaskHeaderMetaCard, with an inline capsule-style multi-line title editor and three explicit rows for title, classification, and metadata.</li>
              <li>Figma priority / status / project / due-date / work-category chips; estimate chip with live progress bar and overtime styling; assigned-label chips with a leading color dot.</li>
              <li>Subdued placeholder chips for every empty state ("No project", "unassigned" category, "No due date", "Add Label") open the corresponding picker when tapped.</li>
              <li>Due-date urgency is tri-state: orange today, red overdue, subdued otherwise.</li>
              <li>Task title now persists in the app bar in subtitle2 once the header scrolls out of view.</li>
              <li>AI Task Summary, Task description, Linked Tasks, and Checklist cards render on a flat TaskDetailSectionCard surface so they visually match the task list.</li>
              <li>TaskLabelsWrapper and the per-chip wrappers that fed the old meta card are removed; shared modal content widgets (status, priority, category, project, due date, labels) are retained and reused.</li>
              <li>Task language selection moves from a flag pill in the header to a "Set language" entry in the pinned app bar's triple-dot menu; the currently selected language's flag renders inline next to the action and opens the same language selection modal as before.</li>
          </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.966" date="2026-04-19">
      <description>
          <p>The desktop navigation sidebar can now be collapsed to a narrow icon-only strip via a menu icon next to the logo. Destination labels become tooltips in the collapsed state and the brand logo hides to free up horizontal space. Drag-to-resize is disabled while collapsed so labels never get clipped at an intermediate width, and the divider still paints its hairline so adjacent panes do not shift across the transition. The collapse flag and the last expanded width are persisted, so re-expanding restores the exact prior divider position and the state survives restarts.</p>
          <p>Priority / status / label pills in the task filter sheet no longer "breathe" when toggled. The pill used to widen its border from 1.0 to 1.5 px on selection, which nudged every sibling chip in the Wrap by 1 px per edge on each toggle. The border width is now pinned at 1.5 px in every state and a 400 ms easeInOut animation cross-fades the border and fill colour alphas between deselected and selected, so the outer dimensions of every chip are identical at every frame and neighbours never reflow.</p>
          <p>Sync startup no longer does every step twice. The connectivity-driven forceRescan and the consumer's runInitialCatchUpIfReady used to race into _attachCatchUp() concurrently because neither acquired _catchUpInFlight for its run, producing two catchup.waitForSync passes, two backfill.start fetches, and two ordered replays of the same event slice. _attachCatchUp() is now the single owner of _catchUpInFlight and the deferred-live-scan flush, short-circuiting concurrent runs with a catchup.skipped (in flight) log. All other entry points now defer to it instead of managing the flag themselves; the obsolete bypassCatchUpInFlightCheck parameter is removed.</p>
          <p>Pre-history gap handling no longer logs per incoming event. Hosts carrying a permanent unresolved prefix used to re-emit largeGapDetected, gapDetectedRange, recordReceivedEntry detected N gaps, and apply.*.gapsDetected for every catch-up event, dominating the desktop sync log. The sequence service now suppresses those lines on incremental extensions of an already materialised range and returns only the newly materialised subrange to callers. A fresh idle restart now logs tens of lines instead of 400 KB.</p>
          <p>Removed the redundant start.catchUpRetry catch-up on every startup: the signal binder's 150 ms follow-up runGuardedCatchUp only runs when the initial catch-up has not yet completed. Once catchup.initial.completed fires, the retry is skipped instead of kicking a second full _waitForSyncCompletion + event-replay pass.</p>
          <p>Connectivity bootstrap no longer duplicates the startup rescan. connectivity_plus emits the current state synchronously on subscribe, which used to schedule a forceRescan racing the dedicated startup rescan. The listener now swallows the first emission while still recording the connectivity signal for metrics.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.965" date="2026-04-19">
      <description>
          <p>DailyOS mobile fix: the DailyOS page no longer surfaces "Failed to load timeline" and "Failed to load budgets" on devices where the v39 migration's partial expression index is missing. The open-task due-date query retries once without the index pin, and beforeOpen recreates the missing indexes on every launch so affected devices self-heal.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.964" date="2026-04-19">
      <description>
          <p>Outbox / sync DB: removed a 40–600 ms main-isolate blocking query triggered on every outbox enqueue (including each image paste or drag-and-drop). getLastSentCounterForEntry used to compute MAX(counter) against an index that did not include counter, forcing SQLite to read every matching row from the heap for hot entry_ids. The v11 schema replaces idx_sync_sequence_log_host_entry_status with a covering idx_sync_sequence_log_host_entry_status_counter, the query is rewritten as ORDER BY counter DESC LIMIT 1 for an index-only scan with early terminate, and the sequence service now caches the last-sent counter per (hostId, entryId) with LRU capacity 2048. Follow-up lookups for the same entry hit the cache and skip the DB entirely; the cache is kept consistent by refreshing it on recordSentEntry. Removes the multi-second UI freeze observed when pasting or dragging images.</p>
          <p>Sync: eliminated the dominant source of redundant work on devices that carry a permanent pre-history gap in the sequence log. Previously, every incoming event on such a host re-ran a multi-chunk scan of the sync_sequence_log table plus a batch-insert pass over thousands of already-materialized rows, and emitted four INFO log lines per event. The sequence log now memoizes the highest counter already materialized as a missing range per host and short-circuits the entire pass when the observed range is already covered; when the observed counter advances, only the incremental delta is scanned and logged. This removes the main cause of severe mobile UI blocking on slow sync queries and the bulk of the daily sync-log volume on desktop.</p>
          <p>Sync: missing or requested rows whose backfill request count reaches the per-entry cap are now retired to the terminal unresolvable status automatically at the start of each backfill cycle. Without this, a permanently unresolvable counter — a pre-history entry, a purged payload, or a mapping whose payload vector clock is permanently behind the requested counter — kept the contiguous-prefix watermark in getLastCounterForHost stuck forever, which in turn forced gap detection to re-enter on every subsequent event for the same host. The watermark now advances past these rows and gap detection stays quiet.</p>
          <p>Sync attachments: the matrix SDK's "File is no longer cached" error used to be emitted as a full exception with stack trace on every replay of an evicted attachment event, with zero recovery value. The ingestor now records the event id the first time this happens and short-circuits subsequent attempts immediately, collapsing bursts of hundreds of error entries per day to one info line per eviction.</p>
          <p>Sync: duplicate in-flight descriptor fetches for the same attachment event are now deduplicated. Two text events referencing the same jsonPath within a single catch-up or live-scan wave previously each launched an independent download, decrypt, and decode; they now share a single future keyed by the index key and descriptor event id.</p>
          <p>Outbox: the sendNext.state and dbNudge observability lines are now coalesced. They emit on state transitions and at a 30-second minimum interval instead of once per tick, removing the majority of steady-state outbox log lines without changing enqueue or send behavior.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.963" date="2026-04-19">
      <description>
          <p>Agent suggestion panel now surfaces the reasoning behind resolved proposals without cluttering the list. A collapsed "Recent activity" strip shows the three most recent ledger entries (newest-first) with verdict icons — check for confirmed, X for rejected, undo for agent-retracted — and when a rejection or retraction carries a reason it lives behind an info icon whose tooltip reveals the text on tap or hover. The strip stays hidden entirely when there is no resolved activity. A "Confirm all" action sits next to the pending badge whenever more than one open suggestion is pending.</p>
          <p>Initial-language auto-apply: set_task_language now bypasses the deferred-confirmation flow when the task has no language set yet, so the agent can pick the language silently on first use. Re-tagging a task that already has a language continues to flow through the standard change-set approval path.</p>
          <p>Suggestion rows no longer display the raw snake_case tool key beneath the human summary — the tool name was developer-facing noise.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.962" date="2026-04-19">
      <description>
          <p>Task agent: the mandatory update_report tool call at the end of every wake is now a hard guarantee instead of a prompt-only request. When the model stops without calling it — a routine failure mode for weaker local models such as Qwen 3.6 served via mlx-vlm — the workflow now issues one additional inference pass with tool_choice pinned to update_report and a direct reminder message, forcing the final report. ConversationRepository.sendMessage and the underlying inference layer gained a threaded toolChoice parameter that overrides the default auto selection policy; the override is currently honored on the OpenAI-compatible path and silently ignored by the Gemini/Ollama/Mistral sub-repositories, which still benefit from the retry's pointed user message. The task-agent scaffold and the seeded report directive also now lead with a non-negotiable "final step" instruction so compliant models need no retry at all.</p>
          <p>Initial-title auto-apply: when the task agent calls set_task_title on a task whose title is still null or empty, the title is applied immediately without a user-approval prompt, so a freshly dictated task lands with a meaningful name instead of an empty-looking suggestion waiting in the panel. Once a title is present the tool reverts to the standard deferred confirmation flow, and a second silent-abort guard inside TaskToolDispatcher no-ops any race in which a manual edit, synced edit, or previously-confirmed proposal populated the title between the LLM emitting the call and the dispatcher running.</p>
          <p>Task agent suggestions are now surfaced in a single consolidated panel on the task detail page instead of two disconnected cards, and the agent itself can autonomously retract its own stale proposals. On every wake the agent receives a unified proposal ledger listing every suggestion it has ever made for the task, grouped into open vs. resolved entries and carrying stable fingerprints. A new immediate retract_suggestions tool lets the agent withdraw proposals that are no longer relevant (the task state already matches them, the user made the change manually, or they duplicate another open proposal) without any user prompt — the item simply disappears from the active suggestion list, leaving an auditable trail alongside user confirmations and rejections. Dedup now excludes retracted items from its basis so the agent can cleanly re-propose after the task context materially changes, while user rejections remain sticky.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.961" date="2026-04-18">
      <description>
          <p>Sync pipeline: removed duplicate-work in inbox attachment handling and sync-family logging. AttachmentIndex.record now dedupes per eventId so repeated observations from live scan, catch-up, and backfill passes become no-ops instead of thrashing the per-path slot between events sharing one relativePath. SyncEventProcessor and SyncSequenceLogService no longer emit each log line twice — DomainLogger is the single emitter and falls back to a direct sync-domain capture when no domain logger is wired. Descriptor catch-up skips events whose relativePath is not in the pending set, so the per-run scan no longer records ~1000 unrelated events into the attachment index. Removed the per-tick OUTBOX enqueueRequest() done log, which fired on every debounced wake and carried no signal.</p>
          <p>Sync pipeline: the per-event apply loop in MatrixStreamProcessor now runs inside a single JournalDb.transaction, so a slice of N sync events commits once instead of N times. Drift coalesces journal-table stream emissions to one notification per slice, collapsing the reader/writer lock contention that produced multi-second waits behind otherwise-cheap id IN (?) lookups during large catch-up replays. Per-event error handling is unchanged: individual apply failures are still caught locally and scheduled for retry, so the transaction only rolls back when a commit genuinely fails.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.959" date="2026-04-18">
      <description>
          <p>Desktop task switcher: switching between open tasks in the desktop split layout now crossfades the detail pane instead of cutting abruptly. The transition is a 480 ms easeInOutCubic fade driven by an AnimatedSwitcher keyed on the selected task id, so it fires only when a genuinely different task is opened — reloads and in-place data updates for the currently open task do not trigger the animation.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.958" date="2026-04-18">
      <description>
          <p>Desktop navigation sidebar: the Tasks and Settings notification counts now render as a design-system number badge in a dedicated trailing slot on the right of each row instead of a Material Badge overlapping the icon and label. Vertical spacing between sidebar items is now 24 px to match the Figma layout. Sidebar rows are no longer pinned to a fixed 48 px height — each row grows with its label, so increasing the OS or app text scale no longer vertically clips "Projects", "DailyOS", "Insights", "Logbook" or "Settings". The mobile bottom-nav preserves its existing overlay badge.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.957" date="2026-04-18">
      <description>
          <p>Database schema bumped to v39 with two new partial indexes on the journal table. idx_journal_tasks_due_open is keyed on the JSON-extracted due date for open tasks so the due-date query streams straight from the index without an external sort, and idx_journal_task_status_private covers countInProgressTasks and similar global task-status counts with a narrow index instead of scanning the full task set. Both partials carry type = 'Task' AND task = 1 AND deleted = FALSE so they stay consistent with the other task indexes and SQLite's theorem prover reliably proves coverage for the paired queries.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.956" date="2026-04-18">
      <description>
          <p>Fix a P0 bug that prevented AI-proposed time entries from being confirmed from the task "Proposed changes" panel. The approval-time validator previously rejected any create_time_entry whose startTime or endTime fell after the originating wake timestamp, which left suggestions like 11:13–11:48 or 11:00–13:00 stuck as pending with a "Failed to apply change" toast whenever the agent rounded or estimated a session past the wake instant. The wake timestamp is still used for the same-day check (so after-midnight approvals keep working), but the "not in the future" cutoff no longer applies at approval time — the user is the authority when confirming. endTime must still land on the same day as startTime.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.955" date="2026-04-17">
      <description>
          <p>Desktop tasks and projects surfaces are aligned with the Figma design system. Sidebar, task list, task details and projects list share the deeper background/01 surface while task cards sit on background/02, and dark-mode text tokens were raised to the Figma-specified opacities (high 100%, medium 80%, low 64%) so headlines, subtitles and timestamps read with the correct contrast without changing type weights. The selected task row now uses the Figma surface/selected token for a subtler highlight, and task group headers and counts use the caption token for a lighter hierarchy. The task title strip and its sliver app bars render on background/01 with no elevation so the header no longer reads darker than the body.</p>
          <p>The sidebar drops the legacy "+ New" quick action, always uses the filled settings glyph, and swaps the Ionicons/MDI nav glyphs for Material rounded/outlined equivalents (Tasks, Projects, DailyOS, Habits, Insights, Journal, Settings). The Insights nav tab now reads "Insights" (English/en-GB) and "Einblicke" (German).</p>
          <p>Task list filter chips use the design-system chip component and render inline under the search bar, with priority chips carrying a leading priority glyph. Tasks and projects filter triggers use filter_list_rounded to match the Figma funnel glyph. Tasks and projects headers are pinned outside the scroll view so the title stays static and pull-to-refresh only drags the list below it. The floating action button is now a rounded-24 teal surface matching Figma, and the journal and task details FABs were swapped from Flutter's default circular FAB to the design-system FAB so list and details FABs share the same shape and bottom-right anchor.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.954" date="2026-04-17">
      <description>
          <p>Optional gzip compression for JSON sync attachments over Matrix, gated by a new config flag that is off by default. Receivers always decompress when the encoding marker is present on an attachment event, so turning compression on for a single device stays compatible with peers on this release. Only .json attachments are compressed; media files are already on compressed formats and skip the branch.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.953" date="2026-04-16">
      <description>
          <p>Raise the open file descriptor soft limit to 10,240 at startup on macOS and Linux. The legacy 256 limit inherited by GUI apps on macOS was trivially exhausted under real-world load, which under slow-network conditions manifested as sporadic EMFILE errors on the Matrix sync pipeline and cascading DNS lookup failures until the app was restarted.</p>
          <p>Startup now logs the soft/hard limits and the adjustment outcome, and EMFILE failures on the attachment save path are annotated with the current descriptor limits so future file-descriptor-pressure incidents are self-diagnosing.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.952" date="2026-04-15">
      <description>
          <p>Task filter modal redesigned with the design system filter sheet. All filter modals now use Wolt modal sheet for consistent adaptive presentation. Selected filter chips show contextual icons for status, category, and label. Priority glyphs updated to match Figma designs.</p>
          <p>Categories, labels, dashboards, measurables, and habits list pages now use design system list items in a grouped container, matching the settings page visual style. Maintenance, logging domain, sync settings, and sync maintenance pages likewise updated. Settings page uses a 3-column desktop layout for wider screens.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.951" date="2026-04-13">
      <description>
          <p>Project one-liner: AI-generated summary subtitle on project list cards, giving an at-a-glance status for each project. The project agent now produces a dedicated one-liner field in its report, separate from the longer TLDR summary.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.950" date="2026-04-11">
      <description>
          <p>Removed the gamey theme and all gamey-styled widgets. Standard Flutter widgets and existing modern cards are used instead.</p>
          <p>Resizable panes in desktop layout: drag dividers between the navigation sidebar and content area, and between the list and detail panes, to adjust widths. Pane sizes persist across sessions.</p>
          <p>Tasks desktop split view now keeps the current loaded list window mounted until refreshed pages resolve, which reduces visible flicker during task saves and other live updates while preserving regrouping after sort changes.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.949" date="2026-04-10">
      <description>
          <p>Dashboard list page redesigned: the old SliverAppBar top bar has been removed and list items now use rounded grouped cards with design system tokens for a modern, consistent look.</p>
          <p>Task list improvements: AI one-liner subtitle shown below each task title for at-a-glance progress, red recording indicator on actively-tracked tasks, and live in-place data updates when editing in the detail pane.</p>
          <p>Removed animated page transitions to eliminate visual flicker during list loads and refreshes.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.948" date="2026-04-10">
      <description>
          <p>Desktop mode: responsive layout switches from mobile bottom navigation to a persistent left sidebar when the window is wider than 960px, with all navigation destinations and Settings pinned at the bottom.</p>
          <p>Desktop split-pane view for Tasks, Projects, and Dashboards: list and detail views shown side by side with reactive selection and active item highlighting in the list pane.</p>
          <p>Checklist filter tabs now include Open, Done, and All. Initial collapse animation on checklists is disabled to prevent jank on slower devices.</p>
          <p>Task filter modal: replaced with the design system version, now includes project filter (grouped by category), agent assignment filter, and search mode toggle (desktop only). Cover art is now always shown on task cards.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.947" date="2026-04-09">
      <description>
          <p>Bottom navigation rollout: every main app tab now uses the Widgetbook design-system bottom navigation shell instead of the legacy Spotify-style bar, with the floating pill centered consistently across the app.</p>
          <p>Mobile bottom sheets and Wolt modals now open on the root navigator on narrow screens so they render above the floating bottom navigation and block tab switching while a modal is active.</p>
          <p>Tasks and Projects now share the same design-system floating action button, and the shared bottom-navigation spacing now lifts floating action buttons and recording indicators clear of the navigation chrome across list, detail, and settings surfaces.</p>
          <p>Task status selection redesigned: a vertical list of rows with icon, label, and a trailing checkmark on the active status replaces the old chip grid. Icons and colours now match the design reference exactly.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.946" date="2026-04-08">
      <description>
          <p>Checklist widget redesigned: progress ring shown in the header when checklist items exist, filter tabs with highlighted selection, plain add-item field, pencil-only edit trigger for items, and fully localized AI suggestion and Share labels.</p>
          <p>Progress ring and three-dot menu are hidden when there are no checklist items. Checklist item rows now expand to accommodate multi-line editing and larger system text scales.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.945" date="2026-04-08">
      <description>
          <p>Standalone soul evolution: dedicated 1-on-1 sessions focused on personality refinement, aggregating feedback from all templates sharing a soul. Accessible via the soul detail page with its own review page and session history.</p>
          <p>Tasks tab migration: added a new design-system browse page behind the <code>enable_tasks_redesign</code> runtime flag. The new route keeps the existing infinite-scroll paging, current filter modal/model, create-task flow, and task-detail navigation while rendering sort-aware grouped sections.</p>
          <p>Tasks tab redesign: aligned grouped cards more closely with Figma by switching to the actual task-status glyphs, inset dividers, priority-section header treatment, tracked-time metadata, and a filter-modal search-mode control in place of the inline full-text/vector toggle.</p>
          <p>Tasks tab polish: replaced the provisional priority glyphs with the actual Figma P0 to P3 icons and restored the intended breathing room below the search row.</p>
          <p>Tasks and projects grouped cards: both tabs now share the same hover and selection row-surface behavior so active rows blend over adjacent dividers consistently, while task category chips now use the same category tag component as projects and the task rows have slightly looser spacing.</p>
          <p>Bottom navigation migration: the redesigned Tasks tab and the Projects tab now render the Widgetbook design-system bottom navigation bar, while the remaining tabs keep the legacy Spotify-style navigation during the rollout.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.944" date="2026-04-08">
      <description>
          <p>Desktop zoom: Cmd+/- keyboard shortcuts and View menu items for zooming the app UI in and out, with Cmd+0 to reset. Zoom level persists across sessions.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.943" date="2026-04-07">
      <description>
          <p>Token usage Stats tab in Agents Settings: iOS battery-usage-inspired dashboard showing 7-day and 30-day token consumption with interactive bar charts, average vs. today comparison, per-model breakdowns, and per-template source activity with high-usage alerts.</p>
          <p>Wake activity chart migrated into the new Stats tab for a unified view.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.942" date="2026-04-07">
      <description>
          <p>Soul evolution UI: standalone soul evolution page with an interactive evolution catalog, soul selector, and a conversation-based refinement workflow for iteratively shaping agent soul documents from templates.</p>
          <p>Pluggable soul document: soul documents can now be customized per agent template.</p>
          <p>One-on-one v2: redesigned agent one-on-one conversation experience.</p>
          <p>Manual planning flow: new "Set time blocks" step for manual daily planning.</p>
          <p>Proposed changes card: removed inline confirm/reject buttons; users now swipe or use "Confirm all".</p>
          <p>Settings page restyled to use design system list items. Context menu aligned with Figma design.</p>
          <p>Projects tab improvements: task rows show agent one-liner summaries, follow-up tasks inherit the parent project, and scroll behaviour is smoother.</p>
          <p>Fixed agents self-notification loops and projects page flickering.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.941" date="2026-04-02">
      <description>
          <p>Agents settings now include a Pending Wakes dashboard with a live badge count, per-wake countdown cards, and per-card deletion for deferred and scheduled wakes.</p>
          <p>The Agents Instances tab now shows a compact task-agent fleet summary under the filters, including current totals for all, active, dormant, and destroyed task agents.</p>
          <p>Task-agent wake prompts no longer inject sibling-task TLDR directories, and the related-task drill-down tool now stays defined in the registry while being hidden from the LLM until a stronger retrieval path is in place.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.938" date="2026-03-29">
      <description>
          <p>Projects detail task summaries: project-task rows now show the latest task-agent <code>oneLiner</code> subtitle between the task title and metadata, matching the current Figma spacing and typography on mobile and desktop layouts, and open project detail pages now refresh automatically when a task-agent report finishes.</p>
          <p>Task-agent reports: the <code>update_report</code> contract now requires a dedicated <code>oneLiner</code> tagline alongside the TLDR and full report so task cards can show a concise current-state summary without reusing the longer report text.</p>
          <p>Projects detail data path: highlighted task rows now bulk-load the latest task-agent reports for all linked task IDs in one repository call, avoiding N+1 report queries on larger projects.</p>
          <p>Projects list grouped cards: category group containers now render the same subtle bordered card treatment shown in the current Figma list designs, instead of relying on background fill alone.</p>
          <p>Projects detail live refresh: when related-task updates reload the derived project detail record, the page now keeps the previous content mounted until the new record resolves, avoiding full-page flicker and scroll-position jumps.</p>
          <p>Projects detail scrolling: the top-level detail route now renders the task panel through a sliver-based lazy list, which keeps large project task lists steadier during fast downward scrolling instead of eagerly laying out every task row.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.937" date="2026-03-29">
      <description>
          <p>Follow-up tasks now automatically inherit the project of the parent task they were created from, both from the UI and from the agent follow-up task workflow.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.936" date="2026-03-28">
      <description>
          <p>Design system navigation: the mobile detail back control is now a reusable component with the intended regular-weight label styling, so detail pages do not drift into heavier back-button text.</p>
          <p>Projects detail task statuses: project-task rows now use the Figma-aligned colored status glyphs for in-progress, done, on-hold, blocked, and related task states instead of flattening every status icon to the same gray tone.</p>
          <p>Projects detail task typography: project-task titles are explicitly kept at regular body-small weight, and the duration plus status line now uses one shared compact caption text style.</p>
          <p>Projects detail task list: task rows now let long task titles wrap across multiple lines and keep duration plus state metadata underneath, with extra vertical breathing room in the Project Tasks header.</p>
          <p>Projects list spacing: widened the grouped project-row horizontal inset so titles, metadata, and status pills sit with the intended breathing room inside each card.</p>
          <p>Projects detail redesign: the top-level Projects flow now opens a new design-system-aligned detail page at <code>/projects/:projectId</code>, with editable category, due date, and status controls, a health-band header, manual agent refresh, an expandable AI report, and the current project-tasks card.</p>
          <p>Projects detail data path: the new detail surface now builds from live project, task, category, and project-agent state while reusing the same shared component tree in the app and Widgetbook. Project-task rows now open task details directly, while the older settings-scoped project views remain in place for category-driven flows during the rollout.</p>
          <p>Projects detail UX polish: category and due-date pickers are now reachable even when no value is set, the empty-state report copy only appears when both summary and full content are absent, and expanded reports strip the leading H1 title that the UI already renders above the report section.</p>
          <p>Projects visual polish: grouped project rows, progress rings, and project-task rows now match the linked Figma spacing more closely, with progress colors driven by completion level and the mobile detail title reduced to the intended heading size.</p>
          <p>Projects tab search: the live top-level Projects page now supports local substring search over the grouped list, and the shared design-system search field keeps typed text stable across rebuilds while centering the search text correctly on mobile and desktop surfaces.</p>
          <p>Task agents now receive parent-project context on wake when a task belongs to a project, including the latest project-agent TLDR and full report body so task recommendations can align with project-level priorities and blockers.</p>
          <p>Task agents now also receive a bounded directory of related tasks from the same project, using stored sibling task-agent TLDRs plus logged time spent, and can inspect one of those sibling tasks on demand through a new read-only drill-down tool scoped to the current wake context.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.933" date="2026-03-27">
      <description>
          <p>Projects tab: the new top-level Projects tab now ships behind the enableProjects feature flag with the intended design-system mobile layout. The live tab and the Widgetbook mobile reference now mount the same sliver-driven header, grouped category sections, and floating create action, while the search field stays disabled pending the later vector-search follow-up.</p>
          <p>Projects filters: the Projects tab and Widgetbook showcase now share the same design-system filter modal, nested field-selection sheet, and state model for project-status and category filtering instead of keeping separate mock-only filter behavior.</p>
          <p>Projects tab reactivity: grouped project snapshots now refresh automatically when relevant project, task, category, or private-visibility updates arrive, so status changes such as Active to Completed are reflected in the UI without reopening the page.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.932" date="2026-03-23">
      <description>
          <p>Projects now show a compact health band at a glance in both the tasks-page project header and project detail page based on the latest project-agent report.</p>
          <p>Linked task activity now marks project summaries stale for the next 06:00 local-time digest, while app state also exposes stale status and active project recommendations for upcoming project health dashboard surfaces.</p>
          <p>Direct edits to a project and task linking changes now use the short deferred project-agent wake path, while other task-level activity stays stale-only until the next scheduled digest unless you refresh manually sooner.</p>
          <p>Projects now also have a top-level tab behind the enableProjects feature flag, reusing the existing bottom navigation and loading grouped project/category data through a single batch overview path.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.931" date="2026-03-23">
      <description>
          <p>Chinese AI Profile: added Qwen 3.5 Plus model and Chinese AI inference profile for Alibaba Cloud with multimodal capabilities (text, vision, audio, image generation). Simplified FTUE setup by removing automatic prompt creation — AI capabilities now use skill-based automation via inference profiles.</p>
          <p>Project agents now track pending project activity in synced state, skip dormant daily digests to save tokens, and show stale summaries in the tasks-page project header until the next 06:00 refresh.</p>
          <p>Project detail pages now show the current project-agent report inline, let you trigger a manual refresh, explain when no project agent exists yet, and return to the originating category instead of the top settings page.</p>
          <p>Confirmed project-agent next-step proposals now persist as active project recommendations that supersede older guidance and can be resolved or dismissed from the project detail page.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.929" date="2026-03-21">
      <description>
          <p>Design system Tabs: added a new Widgetbook-first Tabs component with small/default sizes, token-driven interactive states, optional counter and icon slots, and focused widget/widgetbook coverage.</p>
          <p>Design system Calendar picker: added a Widgetbook-first calendar picker with month rail navigation, token-driven monthly range cells and weekly date cards, plus focused widget/widgetbook coverage.</p>
          <p>Design system Progress bar: added a Widgetbook-first determinate progress bar with default and chunky variants, optional header content, token-driven fill and track treatments, and focused widget/widgetbook coverage.</p>
          <p>Design system controls: tightened accessibility for unlabeled controls, added real tooltip behavior and better truncation to toggles, reset transient interaction states on disable, added a disabled state to split buttons, and now enforce the same visible-label-or-semantics contract across chips, tabs, dropdowns, and split buttons.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.928" date="2026-03-19">
      <description>
          <p>Categories list redesign: new tile layout with colored icon badges, task count subtitles, favorite stars, and private/inactive status indicators. Batch query for better performance.</p>
          <p>Voice-driven time tracking: the task agent can now create time tracking entries from voice dictation, supporting both completed sessions with start/end times and running timers. Entries require user approval before being applied.</p>
          <p>Removed the prompt tab and prompt editing page from AI settings. Prompts are now managed internally.</p>
          <p>Removed the entire tag concept (generic, person, and story tags) along with all related UI, sync infrastructure, services, and repositories. Database tables left in place to avoid migrations.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.927" date="2026-03-16">
      <description>
          <p>Projects UI: full project management interface with create/detail pages, project picker for tasks, category integration, health header on tasks page, and project-based task filtering. Each project auto-creates an AI agent for analysis and reporting.</p>
          <p>Projects feature flag: all project UI gated behind enableProjects config flag (default off). Expandable health header with project/task counts. Interactive status picker on project detail page.</p>
          <p>Matrix sync catch-up: fixed two bugs that prevented cold-restart catch-up from paginating server history correctly, ensuring reliable message delivery after app restart.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.926" date="2026-03-15">
      <description>
          <p>Category AI defaults: categories can now define a default inference profile and agent template. New tasks inherit the profile for speech-to-text/image analysis, and get an agent auto-assigned that waits for content before activating.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.925" date="2026-03-15">
      <description>
          <p>Fixed: Notifications now properly honor the notification config flag. Previously, "tasks in progress" and general notifications were sent even when notifications were disabled.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.924" date="2026-03-15">
      <description>
          <p>Cover art skill: image generation now runs as a background skill via the unified skill pipeline, with fire-and-forget workflow that auto-imports the generated image and assigns it as task cover art.</p>
          <p>Reference image selection: linked-task cover art images are now discovered automatically via bidirectional task graph traversal (with link icon overlay), and the selection limit has been increased from 3 to 5 images.</p>
          <p>Cover art modal: stays open after triggering generation with Siri waveform progress animation; dismissible without stopping background generation.</p>
          <p>Automatic image analysis: newly generated cover art images automatically trigger the image analysis skill, just like a manual photo drop.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.923" date="2026-03-15">
      <description>
          <p>Inference profiles: new "Thinking (High-End)" model slot for tasks where quality matters more than speed/cost (e.g. coding prompt generation). Falls back to the regular thinking model when not configured.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.922" date="2026-03-15">
      <description>
          <p>AI popup menu: skills now appear in a dedicated top section above legacy prompts, with two-section layout and profile-based skill triggering.</p>
          <p>Automatic AI processing: only profile-driven automation runs automatically for audio transcription and image analysis. The legacy category-based automatic prompt fallback has been removed.</p>
          <p>Category details UI: removed the "Automatic Prompts" configuration section. Existing data remains in the database for backward compatibility.</p>
          <p>Skill inference status: SkillInferenceRunner now updates InferenceStatusController so the Siri waveform animation shows during skill-driven inference.</p>
          <p>AI popup visibility: the AI assistant button now appears when either skills or legacy prompts are available for the current entity.</p>
          <p>Preconfigured prompts: stopped seeding <code>audio_transcription</code> and <code>audio_transcription_task_context</code> legacy ASR prompts.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.920" date="2026-03-13">
      <description>
          <p>Sync catch-up: reconnect recovery is now timestamp-first. The client pages backward until the stored timestamp boundary is visible, then replays forward with bounded overlap instead of depending on exact event-id re-anchoring.</p>
          <p>Sync markers: local <code>lotti-...</code> echo ids are no longer persisted as durable remote read-marker ids. Server-assigned Matrix event ids are still kept for remote marker state, while timestamp progress remains the canonical local catch-up anchor.</p>
          <p>Sync pagination: timestamp-first catch-up now keeps paging even without a stored durable event id, and Matrix history requests now honor the configured page size instead of silently using the SDK default page size of 30.</p>
          <p>Sync recovery: automatic backfill now waits until an ordered replay batch settles, and startup keeps live scans deferred while timestamp-boundary catch-up is still incomplete. This cuts redundant repair chatter for offline reconnect bursts.</p>
          <p>Database diagnostics: all Drift-backed databases now log slow queries into daily <code>slow_queries-YYYY-MM-DD.log</code> files when the logging domain is enabled.</p>
          <p>Database indexes: new dedicated indexes for task due-dates, date-sorted task lists, journal browse, definition lists, linked-entry lookups, sync sequence scans, outbox queue scans, and agent database queries. Index-adding migrations now safely recreate existing indexes.</p>
          <p>Journal query improvements: common browse queries use simplified fast-path SQL, task filters use <code>EXISTS</code> predicates instead of <code>CASE</code> branches, linked-child lookups use direct joins, and all-starred/all-private paths bypass redundant filters. Empty selections short-circuit before hitting SQLite, and bulk id-based fetches use an unsorted path when order is not needed.</p>
          <p>Task progress: task-card progress lookups now batch estimates and linked work time spans across visible task IDs through lightweight queries instead of loading full entities.</p>
          <p>Settings database: reads and writes now use a direct Drift executor instead of a background-isolate hop, and same-value saves return early. Settings-key lookups are cached in-process with concurrent cold reads coalesced.</p>
          <p>Config flags: <code>JournalDb</code> keeps a shared in-memory config-flag snapshot so per-flag consumers no longer re-query SQLite after bootstrap. Startup listeners watch only the flags they need.</p>
          <p>AI configs: type-based config watchers derive from a shared in-memory snapshot instead of re-querying <code>ai_config.sqlite</code>, and label-definition visibility checks use explicit private-status filters.</p>
          <p>Daily OS: the unified day view now ignores unrelated database notifications instead of reloading its full bundle on every update.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.919" date="2026-03-12">
      <description>
          <p>Sync inbox: replay of the exact same attachment event no longer re-runs attachment observe/download/write work unless the local file is missing or empty, reducing unnecessary agent payload I/O during catch-up.</p>
          <p>Sync logging: sync-family info logs now go to the dedicated sync daily log instead of inflating the general app log, while sync errors remain visible in both places.</p>
          <p>Sync diagnostics: receiver-side signal logging now emits catch-up and live-scan summaries with source breakdowns instead of one log line per raw scheduler callback.</p>
          <p>Sync backfill follow-up: re-request paging now walks past already queued oldest rows, in-flight backfill requests suppress duplicates, and zombie-file cleanup only deletes files that resolve inside the local docs directory.</p>
          <p>Sync reliability: marker-missing catch-up no longer replays a bounded recent tail as successful backlog. Host progress now stays on the highest contiguous resolved counter, large gaps are fully materialized for backfill, and newly detected missing work nudges automatic backfill immediately.</p>
          <p>Sync convergence: reconnect catch-up now keeps paging until it either finds the stored Matrix marker or reaches the stored timestamp boundary, then replays that ordered historical slice instead of turning an ordinary offline backlog into redundant backfill requests.</p>
          <p>Agent sync startup: when agents are enabled, app startup now keeps agent initialization alive so incoming agent backfill can resolve before any entry or agent screen is opened.</p>
          <p>UI polish: replaced the intrusive automatic rating modal with a pulsating star icon button next to the timer. Fixed provider state mutation during build, RenderFlex overflow, and realtime transcription stop race condition. Removed the label assignment snackbar (now redundant with change sets).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.917" date="2026-03-12">
      <description>
          <p>New task filter: filter by agent assignment (All / Has Agent / No Agent) in the Task Filter Modal. Quickly find tasks that still need an agent assigned. Zero performance overhead when the filter is in its default state.</p>
          <p>Sync fixes: exact backfill hits are now validated against the payload's current vector clock before resend, preventing stale exact mappings from resending a payload and then declaring the same counter unresolvable. When the stored sync marker cannot be found, catch-up now falls back to a bounded recent tail instead of replaying the entire visible room snapshot.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.915" date="2026-03-11">
      <description>
          <p>Removed legacy checklist updates and task summary system — conversation-based processing replaced by agent system. New TaskSummaryResolver with unified fallback logic. Agent report selection now picks the most recently assigned agent. Recorder no longer blocks on transcription inference.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.914" date="2026-03-10">
      <description>
          <p>Local inference fixes: conversation headers now show the actual model name during and after runs. Tool call counts are accurate for all tool types. Resilient JSON parsing for local models. Token usage recorded for Ollama. Prevented tool repetition loops — non-batch deferred tools can only be called once per wake, with guided responses listing remaining tools. Raised default max turns from 5 to 10.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.913" date="2026-03-10">
      <description>
          <p>Fixed macOS crash on quit: use POSIX _exit(0) via FFI instead of Dart exit(0) to prevent VM teardown racing with native threads (mpv, SQLite). Explicitly dispose media_kit Player before exiting. Added 35 new category icons. Polished the icon picker with Material 3 styling. Fixed change set UI stability, label assignment rate limiter, follow-up task handler, and database UNIQUE constraint crash.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.912" date="2026-03-09">
      <description>
          <p>Qwen 3.5 local inference: added 9B and 27B models via Ollama with native multimodal, reasoning, and tool calling. New "Local Power" profile for higher-end devices. Updated default local profile to Qwen 3.5 9B. Removed superseded local models. Fixed Ollama streaming tool call index bug that merged multiple tool calls into one. Added automatic model backfill and profile drift detection on startup.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.911" date="2026-03-09">
      <description>
          <p>Fixed macOS crash on close: skip SQLite database close entirely before exit(0) to avoid SIGABRT in sqlite3_close_v2 during VM teardown. SQLite WAL mode ensures data integrity without explicit close.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.910" date="2026-03-08">
      <description>
          <p>Task agent follow-up task creation with deferred confirmation. Fixed checklist migration placeholder resolution, copy-before-archive ordering, and cascade rejection of dependent items. Added structured domain logging for production diagnostics.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.909" date="2026-03-08">
      <description>
          <p>Vector search distance telemetry: search result cards now show a color-coded cosine distance badge during vector search mode, and distance distribution is logged for threshold calibration.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.908" date="2026-03-07">
      <description>
          <p>Fixed sync backfill: agent entities and links are now included in sequence log population. Added self-request guard to prevent hot-loop. New "Reset Unresolvable" action recovers stuck entries. Host activity cache improves sync performance.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.907" date="2026-03-07">
      <description>
          <p>Agent-proposed labels are now individually confirmable or rejectable instead of all-or-nothing. Rejecting a label automatically suppresses it so the agent will not re-propose it.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.906" date="2026-03-07">
      <description>
          <p>Added an ObjectBox-backed embedding store POC for approximate nearest-neighbor search.</p>
          <p>Switched the current vector backend toggle to the ObjectBox path for macOS benchmarking, including the required sandboxed macOS app-group configuration.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.905" date="2026-03-06">
      <description>
          <p>Unified embedding generation: select multiple categories at once with a Select All toggle. Vector search is now available on the journal tab alongside tasks. Removed the separate "Re-index All Embeddings" action.</p>
          <p>Refactored the embedding pipeline behind a backend-neutral store interface to prepare alternate vector backends without another large call-site migration.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.904" date="2026-03-06">
      <description>
          <p>Fixed embedding backfill failing for entries with code, URLs, or long unpunctuated text by lowering the chunk target to 256 tokens for safer headroom against the model's 512-token context window.</p>
          <p>Sequence log backfill now includes agent entities and agent links alongside journal entries and entry links, closing sync gaps for agent data.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.903" date="2026-03-06">
      <description>
          <p>Fix duplicate checklist suggestions: the AI task agent no longer repeatedly proposes items that already exist on the task, were previously confirmed, or were explicitly rejected. Pending proposals are now included in the agent's LLM context to prevent re-proposing items already queued for review.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.902" date="2026-03-06">
      <description>
          <p>Add one-time backfill of vector clocks on agent entities and links via the Sync Maintenance modal, enabling cross-device sync for records created before the clock-stamping fix.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.901" date="2026-03-05">
      <description>
          <p>Fix cross-device agent sync: task agent provider now reacts to sync notifications so agents appear on other devices without restart. Maintenance re-sync now includes agent entities and links within the selected date range. Removed unused collapsible section from linked entries UI.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.899" date="2026-03-04">
      <description>
          <p>Sync stability fixes: break backfill amplification loop by responding with hints instead of unresolvable flags for superseded counters. Agent entities and links now properly record vector clock counters in the sequence log, eliminating phantom gaps that triggered endless backfill requests and outbox spikes.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.898" date="2026-03-04">
      <description>
          <p>Overlapping document chunking for vector search: long transcripts and agent reports are split into overlapping chunks so every part is semantically searchable. New Re-index All maintenance action rebuilds embeddings with the improved chunking strategy.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.897" date="2026-03-03">
      <description>
          <p>Enhanced agent observations with priority and category fields. Task agents can flag critical grievances and excellence notes for self-correction across wakes and prominent surfacing in 1-on-1 ritual sessions. New high-priority feedback GenUI card renders grievances and excellence notes inline in evolution chat.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.896" date="2026-03-03">
      <description>
          <p>Outbox priority queue: user-initiated actions now sync before bulk operations during large resyncs. Three priority levels (high/normal/low) ensure responsive UX. Sync health reporter logs periodic outbox and sequence counters when domain logging is enabled.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.895" date="2026-03-03">
      <description>
          <p>Simplified audio recording modal: removed Checklist Updates and Task Summary checkboxes. These prompts now always use category defaults when configured. New system setup no longer populates these automatic prompts on categories. Removed automatic task summary infrastructure (scheduled refreshes, smart triggers, countdown UI); summaries are now agent-managed on demand.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.894" date="2026-03-02">
      <description>
          <p>Agent template settings UX: sticky 1-on-1 review button in bottom bar when form is clean, Save/Cancel only when dirty. Full-height directive text areas, clearer profile selector label, and delete action moved to Stats tab. Restored the 1-on-1 review chat FAB so the interactive conversation is always reachable from the review page.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.893" date="2026-03-02">
      <description>
          <p>Voice transcription in evolution chat: mic button with batch and realtime recording modes. Transcript populates the text field for editing before sending.</p>
          <p>Vector search testing UI: toggle between full-text and vector search on the tasks page with timing feedback. Controlled by a feature flag.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.892" date="2026-03-02">
      <description>
          <p>Split agent template directives into separate general and report directive fields for cleaner evolution. Agent reports now support a structured TLDR field shown in collapsed view with full report expandable below.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.890" date="2026-03-01">
      <description>
          <p>Meta-improver agent: recursive self-improvement layer that evaluates and improves template-improver agents. Runs monthly rituals focused on improver effectiveness, directive churn, acceptance rates, and session trends. Includes evolution session feedback extraction, directive churn detection, and recursion depth policy enforcement (capped at depth 2).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.889" date="2026-03-01">
      <description>
          <p>Agent no longer proposes redundant changes that match the current state. Checklist items, estimates, priorities, due dates, statuses, and titles are filtered at proposal time with corrective feedback to the LLM. Cross-device sync of confirmed/rejected change sets now works reliably.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.888" date="2026-02-28">
      <description>
          <p>Inference Profiles: named configuration bundles grouping model assignments per capability slot. Profiles replace direct model references on agent templates and instances. Includes profile management UI, two-page agent creation modal, and six seeded default profiles.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.887" date="2026-02-28">
      <description>
          <p>Agent now learns from past user decisions: confirmed, rejected, and deferred proposals are fed back into the wake context, so the agent avoids repeating rejected suggestions and builds on confirmed preferences. Also fixed redundant label assignment proposals for tasks that already have 3 or more labels.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.885" date="2026-02-28">
      <description>
          <p>Agent sync now uses file-attachment pattern (same as journal entities), preventing failures when agent payloads exceed Matrix's 60KB text event limit. Existing inline messages remain backward-compatible.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.884" date="2026-02-28">
      <description>
          <p>Domain-specific logging with PII-safe sanitization and per-domain toggles in Settings &gt; Advanced &gt; Logging Domains. Defensive fixes for agent wake orchestrator reliability. Agent UI refinements: Beamer-native back navigation, responsive token usage table, improved report controls with countdown timer.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.883" date="2026-02-28">
      <description>
          <p>Checklist user sovereignty: track who last toggled each checklist item (user or agent) and prevent the AI agent from overriding user-set states without a substantive reason citing post-dated evidence.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.882" date="2026-02-28">
      <description>
          <p>Aggregate token usage tracking per template with tabbed detail page (Settings / Stats / Reports) showing per-model summaries across all instances and per-instance breakdowns with lifecycle badges.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.881" date="2026-02-28">
      <description>
          <p>Added token usage section on agent detail page showing aggregated input, output, thinking, and cached token counts per model with grand totals.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.880" date="2026-02-27">
      <description>
          <p>Added bulk-delete button for old AI task summaries with a confirmation dialog showing the count of summaries to be deleted.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.879" date="2026-02-27">
      <description>
          <p>Task-agent linked task context now uses latest linked task-agent reports instead of legacy summaries. Persisted throttle-state refresh now routes through update notifications, and MTTR chart loading de-duplicates linked task lookups with concurrent resolution.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.878" date="2026-02-27">
      <description>
          <p>Settings > Agents page with Templates and Instances tabs, kind and lifecycle filters. Expandable TLDR agent report on task detail page. Agent default model changed to Gemini 3 Flash. Report format aligned with task summary structure.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.877" date="2026-02-27">
      <description>
          <p>Alibaba Cloud (Qwen) as AI inference provider with 5 models including text, vision, reasoning, audio, and image generation variants via DashScope API. Qwen3 Omni Flash for audio transcription.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.876" date="2026-02-27">
      <description>
          <p>Outbox payload size tracking: records total payload size (JSON message + file attachment bytes) for each outbox item, displays size in the outbox monitor, adds daily volume aggregation for sync analytics, and visualizes 30-day outbox throughput in a bar chart.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.875" date="2026-02-27">
      <description>
          <p>Fix task agent automatic trigger broken after throttle optimization: fixed deferred drain silently dropping when deadline expired, added safety-net periodic timer for stuck queue recovery, and fixed startup hydration race cancelling deferred drain timers. Fix agent template model selection not persisted when editing.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.874" date="2026-02-27">
      <description>
          <p>Evolution chat: multi-turn GenUI conversation for reviewing agent template performance and approving rewritten directives. Evolution dashboard with mini charts (success rate, wake history, version performance, MTTR trend). MTTR now measures true task resolution time. Labels in agent reports. Fix assign_task_labels crash and countdown timer digit jitter.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.873" date="2026-02-27">
      <description>
          <p>Agent tools for task language, status, and label assignment. Correction examples and label context injection into agent prompts. Defer-first 120s throttle for bursty edit coalescing. Standardized report structure. ASR re-trigger for parent task notification.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.872" date="2026-02-26">
      <description>
          <p>Agent throttle gate: 5-minute cooldown between automatic agent wakes to reduce token consumption during rapid task mutations. "Run Now" button and countdown timer on task agent chip. Throttle deadline persists across app restarts.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.871" date="2026-02-26">
      <description>
          <p>Fix reference image selection not rendering in cover art generation modal.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.870" date="2026-02-24">
      <description>
          <p>Agent templates: full-stack feature for reusable agent templates with database, service, state, and UI layers. Template evolution workflow with LLM-assisted 1-on-1 review of performance metrics and directive rewriting. Inference provider resolver and settings navigation for templates.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.869" date="2026-02-23">
      <description>
          <p>Provider filter for category prompt selection. Collapsible text entries in linked-entry context. Agent cross-device sync via Matrix with zone-based transaction isolation. Desktop crash-on-exit fix via graceful service disposal. Reference image grid overflow fix.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.868" date="2026-02-22">
      <description>
          <p>Agent cross-device sync via Matrix. Agent entities and links synchronize across devices with wake subscription restoration. Sync maintenance UI supports agent re-sync steps. Zone-based transaction isolation buffers outbox messages until commit, with nested transaction and rollback support.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.867" date="2026-02-22">
      <description>
          <p>Agent running-state feedback with reactive spinner indicators on task page and agent detail page. Tool call arguments and results now persisted and viewable in expandable activity log cards. Conversation view groups messages by wake cycle. Post-execution drain timer ensures signals during execution are not lost.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.866" date="2026-02-21">
      <description>
          <p>Task Agent: persistent AI agents that maintain task summary reports and perform incremental metadata updates via tool calls (estimates, due dates, priorities, checklist items, titles). Gated behind feature flag with dedicated agent database, wake orchestration, fail-closed category enforcement, and agent detail inspection page with activity log and lifecycle controls.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.865" date="2026-02-18">
      <description>
          <p>Real-Time Transcription: Live transcription via Mistral Voxtral WebSocket API with ~2s latency, showing subtitles as you speak. Mode toggle in both AI chat and journal audio recorder. Native WAV-to-M4A conversion on iOS and macOS.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.864" date="2026-02-18">
      <description>
          <p>Checklist Layout &amp; AI Context: Swipe backgrounds now extend edge-to-edge for a polished look. Archived checklist items are now properly marked in AI prompts, so the AI understands they are not active work.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.863" date="2026-02-17">
      <description>
          <p>Archive Swipe Gesture: Swipe right on checklist items to archive them, preserving historical context without marking as completed. Archived items are excluded from completion metrics and hidden in Open filter mode. Swipe left to delete (unchanged).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.861" date="2026-02-16">
      <description>
          <p>Flutter 3.41.1 Upgrade: Upgraded to Flutter 3.41.1 (Dart 3.11.0).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.860" date="2026-02-13">
      <description>
          <p>WAL Mode &amp; Read Pools: Enabled SQLite WAL mode, busy_timeout (5s), and synchronous=NORMAL for all databases, preventing lock errors during multi-isolate access. Added a read pool of 4 isolates to JournalDb for offloading heavy reads. Added background and directory provider parameters to database constructors, preparing for actor-based sync.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.859" date="2026-02-13">
      <description>
          <p>Sync Throughput: Removed artificial 200ms per-message delay from outbox enqueueing and reduced idle threshold from 3s to 1.2s, so sync resumes sooner after user interaction.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.858" date="2026-02-13">
      <description>
          <p>Notification-Driven Streams: Replaced Drift table-watcher streams with notification-driven streams for all entity types, eliminating redundant DB polling and preparing for isolate-based sync. Fixed sync deserialization so unknown enum values from newer devices are logged and skipped instead of retried indefinitely. Fixed config flag init order, late-subscriber tag replay, and theming sync race condition during controller initialization.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.857" date="2026-02-12">
      <description>
          <p>Native M4A Audio: Removed M4A-to-WAV conversion for Mistral transcription. All providers now accept M4A natively, eliminating the FFmpeg dependency and file size quota issues. Updated Voxtral model to reflect Transcribe V2 capabilities (13 languages, up to 1 GB / 3 hours per file).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.856" date="2026-02-11">
      <description>
        <p>Sync Verification Follow-up: SAS emoji verification now updates reliably on both devices, refreshes device keys on completion, and triggers a sync rescan so synchronization resumes immediately without restarting apps. Post-verification trust status now refreshes automatically for a short window so stale "unverified device" indicators clear without manual refresh, and desktop provisioning auto-advances from the QR step to the final status page once trust state is updated. The legacy manual Matrix setup wizard has been removed from Settings; provisioning is now the single onboarding path while keeping emoji/SAS verification in the provisioned flow. Disconnect now shows an explicit confirmation dialog and closes the status modal after successful deletion. Logging performance has also been improved by batching routine log file writes instead of forcing a disk flush for every line.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.855" date="2026-02-10">
      <description>
        <p>Matrix Provisioning Wizard: New sync onboarding flow that lets a desktop device paste or scan a Base64-encoded provisioning bundle, log in, join the sync room, rotate the password, and display a QR code with updated credentials for a mobile device to scan and complete setup. Also includes flexible ratings model improvements where session ratings are now driven by a catalog registry instead of hardcoded questions. Sync room creation now enforces encryption in the initial createRoom request and names rooms with the creating username for easier administration.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.852" date="2026-02-09">
      <description>
        <p>DailyOS Migration and Navigation Fixes: The old Calendar tab has been removed and replaced by the DailyOS tab. The classic calendar day view has been removed and the /calendar route now always opens DailyOS. Tapping a time recording no longer navigates to a session rating instead of the parent task. Session ratings and timer entries now inherit their parent task's category, and the old calendar/DailyOS feature toggles were replaced with a single DailyOS page flag.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.851" date="2026-02-09">
      <description>
        <p>Task Time Fix: When multiple linked entries overlap in time (for example a gym trip that contains a fitness workout), the task progress view previously summed their durations independently, inflating the displayed time. It now merges overlapping time ranges into their union — the same algorithm that already powers the accurate Time Budget view — so task progress and budget views show consistent, correct durations.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.850" date="2026-02-08">
      <description>
        <p>Collapsible Linked Entries: Image and audio entries linked to a task can now be individually collapsed and expanded. When collapsed, a compact preview shows a thumbnail or mic icon with duration alongside the date for quick identification without scrolling past large media. The "Linked Entries" section header also collapses the entire section with a smooth animated transition. Collapse state is saved per link and synced across devices.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.849" date="2026-02-08">
      <description>
        <p>Session Ratings: When you stop a timer that ran for at least one minute, Lotti can now prompt you with a quick rating modal to capture how productive, energized, and focused the session felt, plus a challenge-skill balance check. Ratings are persisted as journal entities linked to the time entry with full sync support. The feature is behind a new "Enable Session Ratings" toggle in Settings, disabled by default.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.848" date="2026-02-08">
      <description>
        <p>Czech Language Support: Lotti is now available in Czech (čeština) with full coverage of all ~1360 UI strings. Platform locale declarations for iOS, macOS, and Windows have also been updated to include all supported languages (Czech, Spanish, French) that were previously missing from the native manifests.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.847" date="2026-02-07">
      <description>
        <p>AI Prompt Optimization: Single-speaker audio transcriptions no longer include an unnecessary "Speaker 1:" prefix - speaker labels now only appear when multiple voices are detected. Checklist generation is now snappy regardless of the AI model: when models like Gemini Flash split items across multiple function calls, they are coalesced into a single batch write for instant UI updates instead of incremental per-item rendering. Image analysis now returns URLs as proper Markdown links and automatically infers https:// when the browser hides the protocol.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.846" date="2026-02-07">
      <description>
        <p>Automatic Image Analysis Fix: Images imported via the photo library or camera roll now correctly trigger automatic AI image analysis when configured on the category. Previously, only clipboard paste and drag-and-drop imports triggered analysis, requiring users to manually open each imported image. Screenshots also now trigger automatic analysis.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.845" date="2026-02-06">
      <description>
        <p>Gamey Design System: A brand-new vibrant visual theme that transforms the app with playful gradients, glow effects, and animations. The Gamey theme includes a full color palette with feature-specific colors, a gradient system with reward tiers (gold/silver/bronze) and neon effects, glow effects at multiple intensity levels, and spring-based animation utilities. A complete set of themed widgets - cards, FAB, settings cards, icon badges, progress bars - all adapt automatically when the Gamey theme is active. The existing theme infrastructure is untouched; the Gamey theme layers on top via GameyThemeBuilder.apply().</p>
        <p>Bug Fixes: Fixed double-tap on Gamey FAB, proper dropdown behavior in theme selection, localized task status labels, correct parameter passing in settings cards, and reliable animation state handling.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.844" date="2026-02-05">
      <description>
        <p>Cover Art Reference Images: When generating AI cover art for a task, you can now select up to 3 images linked to that task as visual references. The AI uses these images to match the color palette, lighting mood, aesthetic, and materials in the generated cover art. For example, if your woodworking task has photos of your project, the generated cover art will incorporate those textures and atmosphere. A new selection step appears before generation - tap images to select them, or skip to generate without references. If a task has no linked images, this step is automatically skipped.</p>
        <p>Bug Fixes: Deleting an image that's used as task cover art now properly clears the reference. Button layout in the image generation modal no longer overflows on smaller screens.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.843" date="2026-02-05">
      <description>
        <p>Daily OS No-Budget Display: Categories without budgeted time now display a cleaner, more compact UI. Instead of showing redundant "0m / 0m" with "0m left" badge plus a separate warning line, categories with no budget now show a single right-aligned "No time budgeted" badge. When time has been tracked against an unbudgeted category, the display shows "Xm / 0m" alongside the badge instead of confusing negative remaining time. All status badges are now consistently right-aligned across budget cards for visual harmony.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.842" date="2026-02-04">
      <description>
        <p>Daily OS Timeline Drag-and-Drop: Planned time blocks can now be moved and resized with intuitive touch gestures. Long-press a block to enter drag mode - drag the body to reschedule the entire block, or drag the top/bottom edges to adjust start/end times. Blocks stay within their visible timeline section and snap to a 5-minute grid. Small blocks use move-only mode to avoid cramped resize handles. Visual feedback includes elevated styling, real-time time labels, and duration indicators. Blocks overlapping compressed regions must be expanded first before dragging.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.839" date="2026-02-03">
      <description>
        <p>Audio Transcription Speaker Fix: When transcribing recordings with multiple speakers, the AI no longer hallucinates speaker names. Previously, the model might guess identities like "John:" or "Sarah:" based on voice characteristics or training data. Now speakers are correctly labeled as "Speaker 1:", "Speaker 2:", etc. The speech dictionary is used strictly for spelling corrections of domain-specific terms, not for identifying who is speaking.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.838" date="2026-02-03">
      <description>
        <p>Daily OS Header Visual Refinements: The time history header now has a cleaner, more polished design. The selected day indicator compactly wraps just the weekday abbreviation and day number instead of extending down over the stream chart. Weekend days use the same compact styling for visual consistency. Vertical dividers between days have been removed for a cleaner look, and the chart is better positioned below the day labels. Selection boxes are wider for improved touch targets and visual balance.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.837" date="2026-02-02">
      <description>
        <p>Daily OS Quick Task Creation: Each time budget row now has a "+" button that instantly creates a task with the category pre-assigned and due date set to the selected day. Tap the button and you're taken directly to the task detail screen for immediate editing. This reduces friction when planning tasks during your daily review - no need to navigate to the tasks screen, create a task, then assign a category and due date separately.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.836" date="2026-01-31">
      <description>
        <p>Daily OS Time History Header: A new horizontally scrollable header replaces the arrow-based day navigation. Tap through days to see a timeline of your productivity, with a sticky month label showing the visible months and selectable day segments with visual selection highlighting. The header supports infinite scroll to load more history (14 days at a time) and includes a Today button for quick navigation back to the current day. Day labels and budget status indicators are visible at a glance. Performance improvements avoid full stacked-height recomputation on each history load unless the scale changes. The stream chart now scales to the maximum daily total with a 6-hour minimum.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.835" date="2026-01-31">
      <description>
        <p>Daily OS Timeline Past Task Indicators: Tasks completed on a different day than the one you're viewing now show a faded checkmark (45% opacity) instead of a hollow circle. This makes it clear at a glance whether a task was completed on the viewed day (full checkmark) or later (faded checkmark). Also removes the italic text styling for completed tasks and now shows P2 (Medium) priority badges alongside all other priorities.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.834" date="2026-01-31">
      <description>
        <p>Daily OS Time Budgets UI Redesign: Slim two-row header design takes up significantly less vertical space. The first row shows category name with a circular task completion indicator and expand/collapse toggle. The second row displays time recorded vs planned, a fixed-width progress bar (now using consistent green/red colors instead of category colors), and status text. Progress bars align in columns for a cleaner table-like appearance.</p>
        <p>Focus Mode Auto-Collapse: When you're inside a planned time block, the matching category's budget card stays expanded while other categories automatically collapse. This helps you focus on the current activity without manual toggling. You can still manually expand or collapse any category as needed.</p>
        <p>Bug Fixes: Fixed a Riverpod state management issue in the focus mode provider that could cause stale data. Added proper error handling when refreshing budget data after a timer stops.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.833" date="2026-01-30">
      <description>
        <p>Voice Task Priority: Set task priority via voice during audio recordings. Say things like "priority P1", "this is urgent", or "low priority task" and the AI updates your task priority automatically. Maps spoken terms to priority levels (urgent/critical→P0, high/important→P1, medium/normal→P2, low/minor→P3). Only sets priority when not already explicitly set, preserving your manual edits.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.832" date="2026-01-30">
      <description>
        <p>Daily OS Timeline: Double-tap planned blocks to edit start/end times. This provides a more intuitive alternative to the existing long-press gesture, opening the same edit modal for adjusting time range, category, and notes.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.831" date="2026-01-29">
      <description>
        <p>Daily OS Smart Timeline Folding: The timeline now intelligently compresses inactive periods to reduce vertical scrolling. Gaps larger than 4 hours between entry clusters are automatically folded, displaying at 8px per hour instead of 40px with a distinctive zigzag edge pattern. Tap any compressed region to expand it. Hours before 6 AM and after 10 PM are folded by default when empty, and a 1-hour buffer around each entry keeps context visible. Days with sparse activity see up to 60% less scrolling.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.830" date="2026-01-29">
      <description>
        <p>Daily OS Overlap Fix: Time entries within the same category no longer double-count when they overlap. For example, a 1.5-hour "Gym Trip" containing a 45-minute "Fitness Entry" now correctly reports 1.5 hours total instead of 2.25 hours. Uses a time range union algorithm to calculate actual time coverage.</p>
        <p>Visual Nesting: Same-category entries that fully contain another now nest visually in the timeline. Child entries render inset inside their parent block, reducing visual clutter. Different-category overlapping entries still display in separate lanes.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.829" date="2026-01-29">
      <description>
        <p>Daily OS Priority System: Tasks now display Linear-style priority badges (P0 red, P1 orange, P3 gray) in both list and grid views. P2 (Medium) is hidden to reduce visual noise. Tasks without tracked time are sorted by priority first (P0→P1→P2→P3), then by urgency, then alphabetically.</p>
        <p>Future Date Filtering: When viewing a future date, only tasks specifically due on that day are shown. Overdue tasks no longer clutter future planning views - they remain visible on today's view for review and rescheduling.</p>
        <p>Timeline Improvements: Entry heights now accurately reflect their actual duration based on calendar scaling (removed artificial 20dp minimum).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.828" date="2026-01-28">
      <description>
        <p>Daily OS Due Task Visibility: Time budget cards now show tasks that are due today or overdue, even if you haven't tracked any time on them yet. This ensures important deadlines don't fall through the cracks. Due tasks display visual badges indicating urgency - red for overdue items and orange for tasks due today. Categories with due tasks but no planned time budget show a warning banner prompting you to allocate time. Tasks are intelligently sorted with tracked-time tasks first, then due tasks by urgency.</p>
        <p>View Preference Persistence: Your preferred task view mode (list or grid) is now saved per category and persists across app restarts. The default view has changed from grid to list for better readability of task details and due date badges.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.827" date="2026-01-27">
      <description>
        <p>Daily OS Task Visualization: Time budget cards now show which tasks contributed time to each category. Each task displays its time spent and completion status (checkmark for tasks completed today). Switch between grid view with task thumbnails and compact list view using the toggle button. The collapsible task section header shows the total task count and combined time. Tasks are sorted by time spent with zero-time completed tasks at the end.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.826" date="2026-01-27">
      <description>
        <p>Daily OS Timeline Overlap Handling: Overlapping time entries now display in separate visual lanes instead of stacking on top of each other. Uses a greedy lane assignment algorithm that places non-overlapping entries in the same lane for full-width display, while overlapping entries get their own adjacent lanes with equal widths and a small gap for visual separation. Useful when tracking multiple concurrent activities like a meeting while taking notes.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.825" date="2026-01-27">
      <description>
        <p>Daily OS Architecture Refactor: Unified data controller for consistent real-time updates. Consolidated day plan, timeline data, and budget progress into a single atomic state that updates together when any underlying data changes. Uses ref.keepAlive() with a manual StreamSubscription to prevent Riverpod 3's automatic pausing behavior. Fixes the auto-update failure where the timeline and budget progress bars wouldn't refresh when time entries were created or synced.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.824" date="2026-01-27">
      <description>
        <p>Day Plan Timeline Fix: Fixed a crash that occurred when calendar entries crossed midnight (e.g., a work session starting at 23:00 and ending at 01:00 the next day). The timeline view now correctly handles overnight entries by treating them as ending at midnight for display purposes. Added defensive bounds checking to prevent the RangeError that caused blank/grey screens on days with late-night entries.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.823" date="2026-01-26">
      <description>
        <p>Daily Operating System: New time management feature for planning and tracking your day. (WIP)</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.822" date="2026-01-24">
      <description>
        <p>Task Time Tracking Fix: Audio recording duration no longer counts toward time spent on tasks. This prevents double-counting when recording meetings (e.g., a 1-hour meeting recording would previously add 1 hour to task progress, even if you also logged a 1-hour time entry for the same meeting). Only actual logged work entries now contribute to task progress calculations.</p>
        <p>Localization: Added missing translations to German, Spanish, French, and Romanian localization files.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.821" date="2026-01-24">
      <description>
        <p>OpenAI Onboarding FTUE: Added first-time user experience for OpenAI providers with one-click setup. Automatically creates 4 models (GPT-5.2 for reasoning, GPT-5 Nano for fast tasks, GPT-4o Transcribe for audio, and GPT Image 1.5 for image generation), configures 9 optimized prompts with appropriate model assignments, and creates a test category with all prompts enabled. Follows the same streamlined pattern as Gemini FTUE.</p>
        <p>Audio Format Simplification: M4A audio files are now sent directly to most providers labeled as mp3, reducing processing overhead. Only Mistral requires actual WAV conversion.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.819" date="2026-01-23">
      <description>
        <p>Code Modularity Refactor: Extracted focused services from large modules for better testability and maintainability. MetadataService handles metadata creation with vector clock integration. GeolocationService manages geolocation addition with race condition prevention. ExifDataExtractor provides pure functions for EXIF timestamp and GPS coordinate extraction. AudioMetadataExtractor handles audio file metadata parsing and duration extraction. Media import is now separated into audio_import, media_import, and image_import with single responsibilities each.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.818" date="2026-01-19">
      <description>
        <p>Voxtral Token Streaming: Upgraded local Voxtral transcription from chunk-level to true token-by-token streaming. Text now appears progressively as it's generated instead of waiting for full 60-second chunks to complete. Tokens are batched in groups of 6 for smooth display without excessive network overhead. The streaming behavior is configurable via Settings → Flags. Non-streaming mode is available for approximately 20% faster processing when real-time progress display isn't needed.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.817" date="2026-01-18">
      <description>
        <p>Mistral Cloud Provider: Added a new cloud transcription option using Mistral's Voxtral API. Supports the voxtral-small-2507 model for high-accuracy cloud transcription with automatic audio format conversion from M4A to WAV for API compatibility. Uses FFmpegKit on iOS/Android/macOS and system FFmpeg on Linux/Windows. The Voxtral model is auto-created when adding a Mistral provider.</p>
        <p>Audio Transcription Improvements: Improved context handling to prevent previous transcripts from bleeding into new ones. Now uses task summary instead of full task JSON for cleaner context. Added explicit instructions that context is for terminology only. Transcriptions now include paragraph breaks on small pauses or topic changes for better readability.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.816" date="2026-01-18">
      <description>
        <p>Voxtral Streaming Transcription: Audio transcription now streams progressively as each 60-second chunk completes. Each chunk's transcription is sent as a Server-Sent Event (SSE), providing real-time visual feedback instead of waiting for the entire audio to process. Particularly useful for longer recordings where you can see progress as it happens. AI streaming responses are now enabled by default for new installations - existing users can enable this in Settings → Flags.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.815" date="2026-01-16">
      <description>
        <p>Voxtral Local Transcription: Added a new local AI transcription service using Mistral's Voxtral model. Supports up to 30 minutes of audio transcription (compared to 5 minutes for Gemma 3N) with 9 languages and automatic language detection. Features context-aware transcription with speech dictionary support for improved accuracy on technical terms and proper nouns. Two model options available: Voxtral Mini 3B (~9.5GB VRAM) for local/edge deployment and Voxtral Small 24B (~55GB VRAM) for higher accuracy. Runs locally on Apple Silicon (MPS) or NVIDIA GPUs (CUDA) with full privacy - no data leaves your device.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.814" date="2026-01-12">
      <description>
        <p>Gemini Setup Dialog Reset Fix: Fixed the reset functionality not working properly. Migrated storage from SharedPreferences to SettingsDb (SQLite) for improved reliability. The reset now takes effect immediately without requiring an app restart. Also localized the reset dialog strings for internationalization support.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.813" date="2026-01-12">
      <description>
        <p>What's New Modal Improvements: Added a "Done" button on the last page for clearer completion flow. The "Skip" button is now hidden on the last page, replaced with "Done" on the right. Button labels now use proper localization (l10n) for internationalization support.</p>
        <p>Cover Art Display: Reverted to BoxFit.cover for better display on mobile devices.</p>
        <p>Dialog Stability Fix: Fixed Gemini setup dialogs disappearing when resizing the app window. Both the Gemini setup prompt modal and FTUE setup dialog now survive widget tree rebuilds during window resize.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.812" date="2026-01-12">
      <description>
        <p>Task Estimate Fix: Fixed the task estimate field not appearing on Linux and fresh installs. The estimate chip was incorrectly hidden when no labels were defined in the app. Now the estimate and "Add Label" controls always appear, regardless of whether any labels exist.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.811" date="2026-01-11">
      <description>
        <p>Gemini FTUE Streamlined: Simplified the first-time user experience by reducing default prompts from 18 to 9 with optimized model assignments. Gemini Pro handles complex reasoning tasks (Checklists, Coding Prompts, Image Prompts), Gemini Flash handles fast processing (Audio Transcription, Task Summary, Image Analysis), and Nano Banana Pro handles Cover Art generation with reasoning mode enabled for reliable image output. The Gemini Setup Modal is now dismissible by tapping outside for a temporary skip - it will reappear on next app start, while "Don't Show Again" still permanently dismisses it.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.810" date="2026-01-11">
      <description>
        <p>Flatpak Fixes: Resolved several console warnings in the Flatpak version. Fixed keyring access error by adding D-Bus permission for org.freedesktop.secrets, enabling secure storage to work properly. Fixed cursor theme warning by exposing host cursor theme paths. Removed invalid fontconfig overrides that caused "Cannot load default config file" errors. Added Flatpak-specific icon path to eliminate application icon warnings.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.809" date="2026-01-11">
      <description>
        <p>Cover Art Fixes: Fixed image cropping on mobile where sides were cut off - now displays full 16:9 cover art without side cropping. Also fixed cover art set/unset not persisting after database sync. The vector clock counter could fall behind synced data, causing updates to be silently rejected. Added auto-catch-up logic that detects stale counters and recovers automatically.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.808" date="2026-01-11">
      <description>
        <p>Voice-Controlled Task Properties: Set time estimates and due dates via voice during audio recordings. Say things like "this will take about 2 hours" or "due by Friday" and the AI will update your task properties automatically. Converts natural language durations to task estimates and resolves relative dates to absolute due dates. Only sets values when not already set, preserving your manual edits.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.807" date="2026-01-10">
      <description>
        <p>Gemini Quick Start: Automatic setup prompt for new users without AI providers configured. Modal appears after What's New is dismissed (no overlapping dialogs). One-click Gemini setup with pre-configured models and prompts. Explains available AI features including audio transcription, image analysis, smart checklists, and task summaries. "Don't Show Again" option persists dismissal permanently. Also notes that other providers like Ollama for local inference are available in Settings.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.806" date="2026-01-10">
      <description>
        <p>Upgraded to Flutter 3.38.6.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.805" date="2026-01-09">
      <description>
        <p>What's New Modal: Editorial magazine-style release notes viewer. Features 21:9 hero banner images with glassmorphism version badges, multi-release navigation with animated indicator dots, and smart "seen" tracking that only marks releases you actually viewed. Includes version filtering to only show releases matching or older than your installed app version, image precaching for smooth transitions, "Skip" button to dismiss all releases, and "View past releases" option to review previous updates. Responsive design adapts to bottom sheet on mobile or centered dialog on desktop.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.804" date="2026-01-08">
      <description>
        <p>Linked Tasks Section: New dedicated UI for viewing and managing task-to-task relationships. Features bidirectional link display with directional indicators (↳ LINKED FROM, ↗ LINKED TO), minimal Linear-style text links with status circles, searchable "Link existing task" modal powered by FTS5, "Create new linked task" for quick subtask creation, and "Manage links" mode for unlinking. Tasks are filtered out from the generic Linked Entries section to avoid duplication.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.803" date="2026-01-08">
      <description>
        <p>Calendar Auto-Refresh Fix: Fixed calendar not updating when returning from creating a time recording. Improved visibility change handling to track transitions from invisible to visible, triggering full provider rebuild only when needed. More efficient than the previous onResume approach with zero CPU overhead when staying on the calendar page.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.802" date="2026-01-07">
      <description>
        <p>Scroll Performance Optimizations: Significant improvements to reduce jank during scrolling. Added cacheExtent to key scrollable views (Entry Details, Tasks List), converted Labels Modal to sliver-based lazy loading architecture, and added RepaintBoundary isolation for task cards, linked entries, and checklist items. Fixed memory leaks in editor widgets where ScrollControllers were being recreated on every build. These optimizations target smooth 60/120fps scrolling, especially beneficial for tasks with many checklist items.</p>
        <p>High CPU Usage Fix (#2578): Resolved infinite rebuild loop in calendar controllers causing 160%+ CPU usage when idle. Removed ref.onResume with invalidateSelf pattern which created a rebuild cycle. Calendar updates are handled correctly by existing visibility and stream listeners.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.801" date="2026-01-06">
      <description>
        <p>Entry Actions Menu Redesign: Restyled to match the FAB addition menu with Nano Banana Pro styling. Features unified list design with subtle horizontal dividers (removed card-based layout), clean icons without gradient containers, and consistent visual language across all modal menus.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.800" date="2026-01-06">
      <description>
        <p>Calendar View Stale Data Fix: Fixed calendar not updating after adding or modifying entries. Root cause was Riverpod 3's auto-pause feature pausing providers when widgets are not visible. Added ref.onResume() callbacks to calendar providers that invalidate themselves when resuming, ensuring fresh data is always fetched when returning to the calendar view.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.799" date="2026-01-05">
      <description>
        <p>FAB Addition Menu Redesign: Modernized the add entry bottom sheet with Nano Banana Pro styling. Features unified dark background (no separate cards), clean white icons without gradient containers, subtle horizontal dividers between items, and edge-to-edge tap effects. Also fixed missing API Key field for OpenAI Compatible provider type (#2570) - authentication section now displays correctly for remote OpenAI-compatible endpoints.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.798" date="2026-01-04">
      <description>
        <p>AI Cover Art Generation: Generate task cover art directly from audio descriptions using Gemini's Nano Banana Pro model. Trigger from audio entry action menu when linked to a task. Full task context (title, checklists, labels, summaries) included in prompt. Review modal with accept, edit, and regenerate options. Cover art display updated to 16:9 aspect ratio at full resolution for consistency with generated images.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.797" date="2026-01-04">
      <description>
        <p>Cross-Checklist Drag-and-Drop Fix: Restored ability to move items between checklists. Fixed regression from checklist redesign where drag gestures were being intercepted. Now uses unified drag system with item-level drop regions for position-aware drops, enabling both within-list reordering and cross-checklist moves via long-press.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.796" date="2026-01-03">
      <description>
        <p>Nano Banana Checklist Redesign: Major UI rewrite with card-based architecture. Features modular widget structure, animated chevron rotation, filter tabs with underline indicator, and three display modes (expanded, collapsed, sorting). Progress ring now hidden when empty in expanded mode. Add input moved to bottom of checklist body with click-to-edit title functionality.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.795" date="2026-01-03">
      <description>
        <p>Image Card Thumbnails: Now display as uniform squares with center crop for consistent visual presentation. Portrait images are cropped from vertical center, landscape images from horizontal center. Also updated Gemini AI models to latest versions.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.794" date="2026-01-02">
      <description>
        <p>Due Date Visibility Refinements: Improved UX for completed and rejected tasks. Due dates are now hidden on task cards for completed/rejected tasks since they're no longer relevant. In the entry details view, due dates show grayed-out styling instead of red/orange urgency colors for completed/rejected tasks.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.793" date="2025-12-31">
      <description>
        <p>Visual Mnemonics: Tasks can now have cover art images for memorable visual representation. Set any linked image as a task's cover art via the action menu. Features include cover art thumbnails on task cards (with filter toggle), a cinematic 2:1 collapsible SliverAppBar in task details, glass effect overlay buttons, and horizontal crop adjustment for positioning.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.792" date="2025-12-31">
      <description>
        <p>Riverpod 3 Migration: Upgraded to Riverpod 3.x with comprehensive codebase migration. Updated all providers to new syntax, added ref.mounted checks after async gaps, converted family providers to constructor-based parameters, and added ref.onDispose cleanup handlers. Fixed disposed ref access errors in autoDispose providers and checklist item resolution.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.790" date="2025-12-31">
      <description>
        <p>Task Due Dates: Tasks now support due date assignment with a date picker in the details header. Features include color-coded status indicators (red for overdue, orange for due today), due date display on task cards with filter toggle, and tappable text that toggles between absolute and relative date formats. Card layout updated with creation date on left, due date on right.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.787" date="2025-12-30">
      <description>
        <p>Habit Settings Fix: Fixed habit settings page opening empty for existing habits. Changed ref.watch() to ref.read() for habitByIdProvider in controller build to prevent rebuilds when stream data changes, preserving form state. Edit flow now loads cached habit data synchronously.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.786" date="2025-12-30">
      <description>
        <p>Habits Page State Refactor: Migrated habits page state management from Bloc to Riverpod. HabitsCubit replaced with HabitsController notifier using keepAlive for app-wide state persistence. Created Freezed-based HabitsState with chart calculation helpers. Updated HabitsTabPage, app bar, streaks, filter, search, and chart widgets to use Riverpod. Fixed search TextEditingController lifecycle and chart touch state handling.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.785" date="2025-12-30">
      <description>
        <p>Audio Player State Refactor: Migrated audio player state management from Bloc to Riverpod. AudioPlayerCubit replaced with AudioPlayerController notifier using keepAlive for app-wide state persistence. Updated AudioPlayerWidget to Consumer pattern and RecorderController to use ProviderContainer injection.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.784" date="2025-12-30">
      <description>
        <p>Habit Settings State Refactor: Migrated habit settings state management from Bloc to Riverpod. HabitSettingsCubit replaced with HabitSettingsController notifier using family provider pattern with habitId as key. Added habitByIdProvider and habitDashboardsProvider. Updated HabitDetailsPage, CreateHabitPage, and related widgets to use Riverpod providers.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.783" date="2025-12-30">
      <description>
        <p>Theming State Refactor: Migrated theming state management from Bloc to Riverpod. ThemingCubit replaced with ThemingController notifier and enableTooltipsProvider. Theme state now uses keepAlive for app-wide persistence. MyBeamerApp updated to ConsumerStatefulWidget pattern.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.782" date="2025-12-30">
      <description>
        <p>Sync Outbox State Refactor: Migrated sync outbox state management from Bloc to Riverpod. OutboxCubit replaced with outboxConnectionStateProvider and outboxPendingCountProvider. OutboxBadgeIcon now uses Riverpod providers for consistency with the codebase.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.781" date="2025-12-29">
      <description>
        <p>Task Sorting and Date Display: Tasks can now be sorted by date (newest first) or by priority using a new segmented button in the filter modal. Optionally display creation dates on task cards with a subtle bottom-right placement. Both preferences persist across sessions.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.780" date="2025-12-29">
      <description>
        <p>Dashboard State Refactor: Migrated dashboard list state from Bloc to Riverpod for consistency with the codebase. Dashboard filtering and sorting now uses dedicated Riverpod providers with case-insensitive sorting for better UX.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.779" date="2025-12-29">
      <description>
        <p>Labels for All Entry Types: Labels can now be assigned to any journal entry, not just tasks. Features include labels display on journal cards, edit capability in detail views, a new "Labels" action in the triple-dot menu, and a unified label selection modal with search and create functionality.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.778" date="2025-12-28">
      <description>
        <p>Twi Language Support: Added Twi (Akan) as a supported language for task summarization. Twi is spoken by approximately 9 million people in Ghana. Enables AI-generated task summaries in Twi with Ghana flag in the language selection UI.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.777" date="2025-12-28">
      <description>
        <p>Image Prompt Generation: New AI response type that transforms audio recordings and task context into detailed prompts for AI image generators like Midjourney, DALL-E 3, and Stable Diffusion. Features visual metaphor guidelines, multiple style options, and a convenient copy-to-clipboard button.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.776" date="2025-12-28">
      <description>
        <p>Task Summary Goal Section: AI task summaries now include a succinct Goal section after the TLDR. This 1-3 sentence description captures the desired outcome or essential purpose of the task, helping maintain focus on the "why" behind the work.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.775" date="2025-12-27">
      <description>
        <p>Single-User Multi-Device Sync: New room discovery feature allows Device B to find and join existing sync rooms without invitation. Includes confidence indicators, smart navigation, and bounded concurrency for faster discovery. Also fixes QR scanner restart after invite failures.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.774" date="2025-12-26">
      <description>
        <p>Calendar Privacy Filtering: Calendar view now respects category visibility settings from the Tasks page. Selected categories show colored boxes with text; unselected categories show colored boxes only (text hidden for privacy).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.773" date="2025-12-25">
      <description>
        <p>Checklist Correction UX: Corrections now use a delayed-save pattern with a cancel option. A 5-second countdown snackbar lets you discard accidental corrections before they're saved as AI learning examples.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.771" date="2025-12-23">
      <description>
        <p>Task Summary Link Extraction: AI summaries now include a Links section that automatically extracts and displays all URLs from task entries with succinct titles (e.g., "Linear: APP-123", "Lotti PR #456"). Links are deduplicated and formatted as clickable Markdown.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.770" date="2025-12-23">
      <description>
        <p>Upgraded to Flutter 3.38.5 with dependency updates. Sync refactoring: OutboxService.enqueueMessage() improved with Dart 3 pattern matching, extracted helper methods, and expanded test coverage (60 → 77 tests).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.768" date="2025-12-23">
      <description>
        <p>Gemini Thinking Support: All Gemini 2.5+ models (including Flash) now display AI reasoning in the Thoughts tab. Plus new usage statistics tracking shows token counts and processing duration for each AI response.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.765" date="2025-12-21">
      <description>
        <p>Sync: Live scans now process strictly after the last marker. The Matrix look-behind tail and its flag have been removed to eliminate redundant work.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.764" date="2025-12-21">
      <description>
        <p>Checklist Deletion Fix: Empty card containers no longer appear after deleting a checklist. The checklist ID is now properly removed from the parent task, and defensive UI filtering handles any existing stale references.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.762" date="2025-12-19">
      <description>
        <p>Sync Catch-Up Concurrency Fix: Prevents concurrent catch-up execution from multiple sources. External forceRescan calls now skip catch-up when an internal retry-driven catch-up is already in flight. Fixes timeout failures that occurred when connectivity triggers ran concurrently with scheduled catch-up retries.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.761" date="2025-12-18">
      <description>
        <p>Sync Catch-Up Fix: All catch-up paths now wait for the Matrix SDK to complete server sync before processing. Fixes issue where catch-up after extended offline periods would miss entries. Includes automatic follow-up for slow networks.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.758" date="2025-12-18">
      <description>
        <p>Sync Gap Detection Fix: Prevents false positive gap detection during reconnection. Covered vector clocks are now processed before gap detection, and live scan signals are deferred during catch-up to ensure in-order event processing.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.757" date="2025-12-16">
      <description>
        <p>Nested AI Responses: Generated prompts from audio entries now display directly beneath them in an expandable section. Includes smooth collapse/expand animation and swipe-to-delete with confirmation.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.754" date="2025-12-15">
      <description>
        <p>Sync Backfill Improvements: EntryLink support ensures all sync message types are tracked and can be recovered. Ghost missing entry resolution handles cases where different message types share the same sequence counter.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.753" date="2025-12-14">
      <description>
        <p>Add prompt type for creating prompts, for example for feeding into Claude Code, Codex and
            similar tools, or ChatGPT, Gemini, Claude in research mode.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.752" date="2025-12-06">
      <description>
        <p>Sync Backfill: Request missing journal entries from connected devices during sync to ensure complete synchronization across all your devices.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.751" date="2025-12-05">
      <description>
        <p>Automatically create Gemini prompts.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.750" date="2025-12-05">
      <description>
        <p>Multiple improvements and simplifications in Sync code.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.747" date="2025-12-01">
      <description>
        <p>Automatic Image Analysis: Drop, paste, or import images to a task and they're analyzed automatically. Smart Task Summaries: Your first task summary is created immediately when you add meaningful content (image analysis, audio transcription, or text). No more manual checkbox clicks—just work naturally and let the AI keep up.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.746" date="2025-12-01">
      <description>
        <p>Checklist Correction Examples: The AI now learns from your manual corrections. When you fix a checklist item title (like "test flight" to "TestFlight"), Lotti remembers and uses these examples to improve future AI suggestions for both checklist updates and audio transcription.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.745" date="2025-11-30">
      <description>
        <p>Speech Dictionary per Category: Teach the AI your domain-specific terms. Add names, places, and technical words to a category's dictionary, and transcriptions automatically use the correct spellings. Select misrecognized text and add corrections via the editor context menu.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.744" date="2025-11-29">
      <description>
        <p>Smarter AI checklist updates: Say "I did the shopping" and the AI marks the right item complete. Mention "fix the typo in iPhone" and it corrects transcription errors. The AI now understands what you mean, not just what you type.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.743" date="2025-11-29">
      <description>
        <p>Improved task search field width and layout for better use of available space.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />
  <categories>
    <category>Office</category>
    <category>ProjectManagement</category>
    <category>Calendar</category>
  </categories>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>Lotti application interface</caption>
      <image type="source" width="536" height="999">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/matthiasn/lotti/8a5b9ef0f9d8e7132638f497107bc33215819c0d/flatpak/screenshot.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
</component>
